RYAN REYNOLDS: All right...
(LAUGHS) Welcome to the Deadpool
home entertainment commentary.
PAUL WERNICK: Has a nice ring to it.
REYNOLDS: Thank you.
Uh, this is Ryan Reynolds.
I'm here with Rhett Reese
and Paul Wernick.
WERNER Hello.
REYNOLDS". The screenwriters of
the Deadpool cinematic festival.
Just to set the tone, we're at my house.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
We're in the basement of my house.
WERNER Where we've been
for the last, uh, 14 months
you've had us locked down here?
REYNOLDS: Yes,
where I've had these guys, uh...
So, if you hear... We're in my house,
so if you hear dogs barking or something
or if you hear an elderly
door-to-door salesman
who sounds like he's tied up with a ball gag
-and several other things...
-(WERNICK LAUGHS)
...just carry on.
It should also be known that we have
a life-size Deadpool in the room with us.
The suit that I stole while shooting the film,
I brought home with me
and is basically, sort of,
presiding over the commentary.
WERNICK: What year was
the Sexiest Man Alive, Ryan?
REYNOLDS: For me or Hugh Jackman?
WERNICK: You, you.
REYNOLDS: For me, it was 2010.
-For Hugh Jackman, 2008.
-WERNICK: Mmm.
-Both great years.
-REYNOLDS: And I saw Hugh the other day
and somebody made a joke about that
and we couldn't tell you
who the other guys were,
which is sort of...
RHETT REESE: Oh, sure, sure.
REYNOLDS: (CHUCKLES) I'm kidding.
I've got all the issues right here.
(REESE LAUGHING)
REESE: Does anyone want to talk about
what inspired the credit scene here?
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
WERNICK: This was a, uh,
Philips Carousel advertisement
directed by, I think, Adam Berg?
REYNOLDS". Yup. Adam Berg.
Yeah, that's what inspired this.
This is six years old, basically.
This has been in the script forever.
This song was the first song
we had in the script as well, right?
WERNICK: It was.
REYNOLDS: Yup.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Angel of the Morning by Juice Newton.
WERNER Which will introduce Juice
to a whole new generation
which we're most excited about.
REYNOLDS: It's true.
-That's very, very true.
REESE". And this is, of course,
100% CGI.
Tim Miller originally wanted to do
the vast, vast majority of the movie
in a computer entirely.
Am I wrong?
REYNOLDS: He actually wanted to...
Because he'd never directed a film before,
he wanted to do a CGI version
of the entire movie first
(SONG PLAYING IN HINDI)
before we set foot on this
and practically shot it,
which he soon realized
was totally ludicrous and impractical.
But a great idea.
Be nice if we could do that.
And our cab here.
(WIND WHOOSHING)
But also that opening credit sequence
was in the movie
and then out of the movie,
then in the movie
and thank God it stayed in, in the end.
'Cause we love it.
That's Tim Miller's gum, by the way.
That is the director's real gum
that was on the ceiling of the, uh...
-WERNICK: Is that right?
-...cab. Yes. Yes, it was.
Kinda lonesome back here.
(GRUNTS) Yeah, little help.
(MUMBLING)
Okay, um, just, I have to keep my hands...
Okay, um, just, I have to keep
my hands on the wheel.
WERNER As actors in that
opening credit sequence,
did you need to have waivers for that
(CONTINUES GRUNTING)
Excuse me. Whoo!
in terms of not having your name
on the opening titles?
(CHUCKLES) Ah, Dopinder.
Pool. Dead.
REYNOLDS: No, we didn't.
As long as you didn't use
anyone else's real name, it's fine.
Hmm, nice.
DOPINDER:
Smells good, no?
Not the Daffodil Daydream. The girl.
Not the Daffodil Daydream.
The girl.
-Ah, yes. Gita. She is quite lovely.
-Hmm.
Ah, yes. Gita.
Hmm.
She is quite lovely.
She would have made me
a very agreeable wife.
But, um...
REYNOLDS". Should I say
where the name Dopinder comes from?
Gita's heart has been stolen
by my cousin Bandhu.
WERNICK". Please, yes.
REYNOLDS". The name Dopinder is a guy
that I went to elementary school with,
He is as dishonorable
as he is attractive.
who unfortunately died
being struck by lightning.
Dopinder, I'm starting to think
I'm not making that up.
there's a reason
I'm in this cab today.
Yeah, sir, you called for it, remember?
Yeah, sir, you called for it,
remember?
No, my slender brown friend.
Love is a beautiful thing.
REYNOLDS". And he was a buddy of mine,
and I, sort of, pay homage to him
When you find it,
the whole world
by using his name here in the movie.
tastes like Daffodil Daydream.
(DOPINDER GRUNTS)
He's now immortalized by Karan Soni,
who plays our Dopinder.
So you gotta hold onto love...
...tight!
Ah.
And never let go.
Don't make
the same mistakes I did.
-Got it?
-Yeah.
Got it?
Yeah.
WERNICK: Karan actually, uh...
My daughter found Karan. (CHUCKLES)
Or else the whole world tastes
like Mama June after hot yoga.
Sir, what does Miss Mama June
taste like?
(STUTTERS) Sir, what does
Miss Mama June taste like?
WERNER He was in the AT&T ads,
and she loves him
Like two hobos fucking in a shoe
filled with piss. Okay, enough.
I can go all day, Dopinder.
The point is, it's bad!
-and thought he was so funny.
-REYNOLDS: Hmm.
Hmm, it's bad.
-She was the one who recommended...
-REYNOLDS: Really?
Uh, why the fancy
red suit, Mr. Pool?
...him to me and then me
to the casting director
Oh, that's because
it's Christmas Day, Dopinder.
-and then he came in. Yup.
-REYNOLDS: Ah, I didn't know that.
And I'm after someone
on my naughty list.
God, he was such a find.
I've been waiting one year,
three weeks...
-He was so, so great. Yeah.
-WERNICK: So great.
six days and, oh...
14 minutes to make him fix
what he did to me.
REESE: Dopinder is talking
about the red suit here.
Should we talk a little bit about the suit
And what did he do
to you, Mr. Pool?
and your reaction to
the first time you saw it?
This shit...
REYNOLDS: Yeah, that's, um...
Oh, God.
Boo!
The suit made me weep
the first time I saw it.
(CHOPPER BLADES WHIRRING)
In fact, it was, uh...
REESE: And subsequently made you weep
every time you had to put it on.
REYNOLDS: That's true.
At the beginning of the film,
it took about 40 minutes to put it on,
and by the end, I had that down to 10.
But it is a work of art, that suit. It truly is.
Russ Shankle at Film Illusions created it.
(SIGHS)
I think it's the most faithful
They won't disappoint.
comic-book-to-screen adaptation
of a super suit ever.
They'd better not.
And what about
next month's shipment?
REESE: Absolutely.
REYNOLDS: I love it.
REESE: It's just awesome.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
There won't be one.
WERNICK: How many suits
were there, Ryan?
You're not the only one
with a war to win.
REYNOLDS: There were nine suits.
That won't do.
We destroyed seven of them
shooting the film.
See, we've had
this small disruption
And one of the two remaining suits
I left with at the end of filming.
to our supply chain...
(CHOKING)
That's the one that is presiding
over our commentary right now.
We'd appreciate your patience.
I just walked off set with it
and basically told them
to go fuck themselves.
-WERNICK: Yeah.
-I waited 10 years to do the movie...
(GRUNTS) Okay.
REESE: Broke a few laws.
We'll deliver in full
the following month.
REYNOLDS". If they want to
take the suit back,
they can come try and take it from me.
(GASPING)
I was in very good shape
when I shot the Deadpool movie
Pleasure doing
business with you.
and I felt confident that I could take out
a 107-pound studio executive.
REESE: And contrary
to what you might think,
Fucking mutant.
you could see out of it pretty well,
(ENGINES ROARING)
and we could also hear you talking
without it seeming too muffled.
It was a pretty...
REYNOLDS". I do feel like we had some
dumb luck with the suit there.
We really got lucky.
Oh, shit!
You can hear Deadpool very well
and I could see very well.
I forgot my ammo bag.
Shall we turn back?
REESE: Yeah.
No, no time.
REYNOLDS: We had
two different sets of eyes.
Fuck it. I got this.
9, 10, 11, 12 bullets,
or bust.
We had the stunt eyes for the suit,
which the black part was sort of a mesh.
Right here!
(GRUNTS)
I could see through it.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
And then for close-ups,
I used an opaque eye mask.
That's, uh, $27.50.
So that's an opaque one.
I... I never carry a wallet
when I'm working.
You can't... Just the white part
was the only piece I could see through.
Ruins the lines
of my suit.
Oh.
But, uh,
how about
a crisp high five?
WERNICK: And the eyes pop out, right?
Okay.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, they're magnetic.
Merry Christmas.
They actually clip on with magnets.
And a convivial Tuesday
in April to you too, Pool!
REESE: And if you're wondering why
Deadpool seems so expressive in the suit,
♪ Hey, yeah
I wanna shoop, baby
a part of that is Ryan's genius physicality
(WADE SINGING)
♪ Shoop shooop ba-doop, shoop ba-doop
-in acting within the suit.
-REYNOLDS: Thank you.
♪ Shoop ba-doop,
ba-doop, ba-doop
REESE: But it's also the fact that
they did some facial motion capture.
♪ You're packed and you're
stacked 'specially in the back
♪ Brother, wanna thank your
mother for a butt like that
And they actually used CG
to animate the face in specific scenes
♪ Can I get some fries
with that shake-shake boobie?
♪ If looks could kill
you would be an uzi
so that Deadpool can make expressions,
♪ You're a shotgun, bang! ♪
like his eyes open right there,
for instance, just a little bit.
Wha... Oh!
Oh, hello. I know, right?
That's actually done in a computer
Whose balls
did I have to fondle
because the suit itself
is not that expressive.
to get my very own movie?
I can't tell you,
WERNICK: Hmm.
but it does rhyme
with "Polverine."
(REYNOLDS LAUGHS)
And let me tell you,
he's got a nice pair of
smooth criminals down under.
WERNICK: Ryan's Australian accent.
REYNOLDS: (IN ACCENT) Do you like it?
WERNICK: Absolute favorite.
Anyway, I got places to be,
a face to fix and, oh...
REYNOLDS: Like to have a good time
-with my Aussie accent.
-(WERNICK AND REESE LAUGHING)
REYNOLDS: Just get right in there
and do a little Hugh Jackman.
Bad guys to kill.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
-(REYNOLDS CHUCKLING)
-WERNICK This was originally
uh, conceived in a computer
Maximum effort.
as test footage we did.
REYNOLDS: (IN NORMAL VOICE)
This is pan' of the infamous test footage.
WERNICK: That leaked online.
(GROANS)
We did it, I think, what, 2011
we did the test for Fox?
(GRUNTING)
REYNOLDS: Yup.
REESE: Yeah.
Tim Miller was...
WADE: Cock shot.
I believe he got, what, $300,000?
-Something like that?
-WERNICK: Something...
(SCREAMING)
REYNOLDS: (STAMMERS) $275,000.
REESE: $275,000 to prove to the studio
(MOCKINGLY) Ha!
that he could handle the movie,
(GRUNTS)
Rich Corinthian leather.
and he did this wonderful test.
It was so wonderful,
but the public never saw it, so...
WADE: I'm looking for Francis!
Have you seen this man?
(GROANS)
We started all hatching a plot.
Ow. Ow. Ow. Ow.
(RADIO STATIONS CHANGING)
We were having difficulties
getting the movie green lit.
We started hatching a plot
to leak the footage.
REYNOLDS: (STUTTERS)
Are you... You're, um...
WADE: Ow. Ow!
REESE: And when I say "hatching a plot, "
Yanky, yanky!
none of us was
technologically savvy enough
(GUN FIRES)
(SCREAMS)
-to actually leak it.
-REYNOLDS: To figure out how to do that.
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
REESE: Each of us was trying to
convince the others to do it for him.
REYNOLDS: I think that's what's...
That's the story we're telling each other,
but I think one of us...
(WADE GASPS)
(GROANS)
-I believe that one of us did it.
-WERNICK: Ryan Reynolds.
REYNOLDS: One of us leaked that footage.
WERNICK: Ryan Reynolds.
(SCREAMS)
(MAN GROANING)
(CAR ACCELERATING)
-His name rhymes with Bryan Breynolds.
-(REESE LAUGHS)
(GRUNTING)
REYNOLDS: "Bryan Breynolds".
REESE: I mean, it's a...
It's kind of like a game of Clue.
There are only about six or seven suspects,
(TIRES SCREECHING)
so you know, somebody was in
the dining room with the candle stick.
REYNOLDS". Absolutely.
(CONTINUES GRUNTING)
And that...
(SCREAMING)
WERNER Which probably
is worth talking about...
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
REYNOLDS: That was fun.
WADE: I've never said this,
but don't swallow.
WERNICK: Kind of the evolution of the
long process of getting this movie made
because, again, we're talking now 2011,
which was five years ago.
(MAN GROANING)
(GUN COCKS)
REYNOLDS; Yeah.
WERNICK Um...
(GRUNTS)
And the movie, Ryan,
has been in development, what...
You were first brought the comics,
what, in...
REYNOLDS: I was...
WERNICK: 2003?
REYNOLDS: 2004.
WERNICK: 2004.
REYNOLDS". I've been involved
with DeadpooL
Shit.
or attached to some aspect
of Deadpool development
Did I leave the stove on?
for, uh, 11 years
before actually making the movie, so...
WERNICK: And it came to you when?
When you were doing Blade, right?
(THUDS)
REYNOLDS: It came to me
when I was doing Blade: Trinity.
Say what you will about that movie,
but it brought me great things.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
It actually was a lot of fun.
I got to improvise a lot and goof around.
REPORTER: Now, breaking news.
Uh, looking back at it, you know,
I look back at it and I think,
A multi-car collision
turned shots fired
"I was kind of, in a weird way,
playing Wade Wilson in that movie
on the crosstown expressway
this morning.
Gridlock has kept
police from the scene.
"and I didn't know it."
Residents are advised
to remain in their homes.
Someone else did, though.
That's who sent me the comic book...
The stack of comics.
The assailant
appears to be armed,
dangerous, and wearing...
I was sent them and a guy...
a red suit.
A red suit.
And he said, "You're Deadpool."
Deadpool.
I said, "Who's Deadpool?"
Negasonic!
Come, we have mission.
And he said,
"You should read these comics.
"If they ever make a Deadpool movie,
you're the guy."
NEGASONIC TEENAGE WARHEAD:
Colossus, wait up.
And I read them and I fell in love with it.
I've given Deadpool
every chance to join us...
That was in 2004 when that panel came out
on the Deadpool comic
but he'd rather
act like a child.
that said... Asking what Deadpool,
what he looks like.
A heavily-armed child.
When will he grow up and see
benefits of becoming X-Man?
And he said, "I'm a cross between
Ryan Reynolds and a shar-pei."
Which benefits?
The matching unitards?
-(REESE LAUGHS)
-That was son' of kismet I thought, so...
The house that blows up
every few years?
Please.
WERNICK: And then it moved over to Fox.
House blowing up
builds character.
You ate breakfast, yes?
WERNICK: Correct?
REYNOLDS: Yes.
Breakfast is most
important meal of day.
WERNICK: 'Cause it was
at New Line, was it not?
REYNOLDS". I think it was at New Line,
was where it was at initially.
Here, protein bar.
Good for bones.
Avi Arad had it, actually.
No, I don't know if it was actually
at a studio home.
Deadpool may try
to break yours.
Avi Arad owned Marvel at the time and...
(JET ENGINE ROARING)
A little startup called Marvel
that seemed to do all right.
Uh, and then, yeah, eventually it was at Fox
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
MAN: Get out of the way!
with all the other X-Men properties,
so, yeah.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING
AND SCREAMING)
WERNICK: And we wrote the script in 2009.
REYNOLDS: Yup.
WERNER And a draft of the script
in every calendar year since.
REYNOLDS: (LAUGHS) Yeah. Right. Yeah.
WERNICK Truly.
-2009 to 2016...
-REYNOLDS: But the script has largely...
The storylines
have largely stayed the same.
WADE: Hey! Whoo!
(GUNS FIRING)
WERNER Interestingly, if you go back
and read our first draft of the script
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
and then you watch the movie,
it's not that different.
-I mean...
-REYNOLDS: Just more expensive.
WERNICK: A lot more expensive.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, the old version
was too expensive.
WADE: Wait!
WERNICK: At one point,
we had a PG-13 version.
You may be wondering,
"Why the red suit?"
Fox commissioned us
Well, that's so bad guys
can't see me bleed.
-to write a PG-13 version...
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
-It was six pages long.
-(WERNICK LAUGHS)
This guy's got the right idea.
REESE: The character of Angel Dust,
played by Gina Carano,
He wore the brown pants.
(GUN FIRING)
Fine!
I only have 12 bullets...
was actually three different characters.
It was Garrison Kane, Wyre and Sluggo.
so you're gonna
have to share!
Let's count them down.
REYNOLDS". Yeah.
REESE". If you remember that.
REYNOLDS: Sluggo, yeah.
(GUN FIRING)
REESE: For budget reasons,
we did away with two
and changed the third to Angel Dust.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
(GROANING)
REESE: We ended up adding
Negasonic Teenage Warhead much later.
(FIRING CONTINUES)
REYNOLDS: True.
(GROANS)
REESE: She was
not in the original draft.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
But Colossus was always there.
REYNOLDS". This entire sequence
is shot on a viaduct
Shit.
in Vancouver, British Columbia,
where I grew up.
Motherfucker!
This is my hometown.
And I became
public enemy number one, uh,
10! Shit!
Nine. Fuck.
because we cocked up the traffic
in Vancouver for two and a half weeks
Eight.
Shit-fuck!
(GRUNTS)
while we took over this bridge.
Uh, somehow, I got thrown under the bus
with that. (CHUCKLES)
Bad Deadpool.
Seven.
Good Deadpool.
AH the media in Vancouver
was blaming me for the issues,
(BULLETS RICOCHETING)
which I guess, to some degree,
it is my fault.
WERNICK'. Kind Of your fault.
REYNOLDS". I do apologize to the citizens
of Vancouver, British Columbia.
WERNICK: We shot
the entire movie in Vancouver.
(GUN COCKS)
Oh!
REYNOLDS: Yeah, it was great.
Good city to shoot in. Great crews.
(GRUNTS)
REESE: I think we feel that
whenever you're writing an action scene,
(GUN CLICKING)
Someone's not counting. Six.
(GROANS)
you want to stack the odds
against your hero.
REYNOLDS: That guy right there
who I just shot in the head,
he was my double in Blade.
-He was my stunt double.
REESE". Oh, is that right?
REYNOLDS: That was my main
stunt double in Blade.
REESE: Wow.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
(GUN FIRING)
Yeah.
(EXPLODING)
REESE: But yeah, we always like to
stack the odds against the hero,
and we did it in this scene
by reducing Deadpool's ammunition supply
to only 12 bullets.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
Oh!
And we just put him in a predicament.
How do you use 12 bullets
-to kill a bunch of guys?
-REYNOLDS: Mmm-hmm.
WERNICK: It's the only sequence
Deadpool shoots a gun.
(GROANS) Four...
(GUN FIRES)
(GROANS)
Gotcha.
Is that correct?
(GRUNTS)
REYNOLDS". Pretty much. Yeah.
Right up main street.
WERNICK: Otherwise it's katanas.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
REYNOLDS". Well, other...
Right at the very end of the film...
WERNICK: Oh, yes.
REYNOLDS: One bullet.
Three, two!
WERNICK: One bullet. Spoiler alert.
Stupid! Worth it.
REYNOLDS". But, um,
we do love the katanas.
I got shot in the asshole there,
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
which right up until a week
before shooting that sequence,
it was in the face.
WERNICK: Yeah.
REYNOLDS: And then we changed it.
We just thought asshole would be
a lot funnier.
WERNICK: Ryan had the idea
that getting shot in the ass was so funny
(GUN FIRES)
and it gets a huge laugh.
(ALL GROANING)
REYNOLDS". I was trying to find some way
to work in "Right up Main Street."
(CLINKS)
-WERNICK: Such a great line.
-(REYNOLDS CHUCKLES)
(SNIFFING)
Oh, yeah.
Ah!
WERNICK: He shoots one gun there
I'm touching myself tonight.
and both are smoking.
Francis!
REYNOLDS: We have both barrels
smoking, so...
Francis...
'Cause we're complete ass wipes.
What the shit-biscuit!
Where you at, Francis?
Where you at,
Francis?
REYNOLDS: Oh, yeah.
(GROANING)
That's Glenn.
He's about to get it.
(GROANING LOUDLY)
He's about to get what he deserves.
WERNER You do training
with the katanas, Ryan, beforehand?
You're not Francis.
I can't remember.
I know you did it going into
the Wolverine movie.
REYNOLDS: I did...
WERNICK: Did you do it on this one?
REYNOLDS: I did a lot of it
on Wolverine and then I...
Really?
Rolling up the sleeves?
Yeah, I did, you know...
There's only so much you can do
with katanas
and this is one of them,
which is spinning them around like that.
(GROANS)
But, yeah, I like doing it.
I like the katana stuff.
WERNER. And you have some katanas
in the house
WADE: You're
probably thinking,
from Wolverine, don't you?
"My boyfriend said
this was a superhero movie...
-Didn't you take the katanas?
-REYNOLDS: I did take the katanas.
"but that guy in the red suit
just turned
WERNICK: You steal everything.
"that other guy
into a fucking kabab!"
-You're a little bit of a kleptomaniac.
REESE". Yeah, I was gonna say.
Well, I may be super,
but I'm no hero.
You're a serial...
REYNOLDS: In a fitting piece of destiny,
those were stolen from me.
And yeah, technically,
this is a murder.
WERNICK: Were they?
REYNOLDS: I moved and, yeah,
somebody stole the Wolverine...
But some of the best love
stories start with a murder.
-(CLICKS TONGUE) ...katanas
-WERNICK: That's a huge bummer.
And that's exactly
what this is, a love story.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
But, right next to you
are actually a pair of katanas
And to tell it right...
I gotta take you back
to long before
that are stolen from...
On the DeadpooL right there.
I squeezed this ass
into red spandex.
WERNER Oh, okay.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Oh, those jeans.
MERCHANT: Look, would it help
if I slow it down for you?
WERNICK: Great.
REESE: That was our ass-to-ass transition.
REYNOLDS: Yup.
I didn't order the pizza.
Is this 7348 Red Ledge Drive?
Are you Mr. Merchant?
REESE: A nod to Requiem for a Dream.
(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
Yeah, the Mr. Merchant who
didn't order the fucking pie!
REYNOLDS: A nod to Fellini.
Then who placed the call?
WADE: I did!
(TOILET FLUSHING)
REYNOLDS". It always bugged me
that I flushed the toilet
Pineapple and olive?
after telling him I just took a shit
in his kitty litter box.
Sweet and salty.
-WERNICK Yeah.
-(REYNOLDS LAUGHS)
The fuck are you?
The fuck you doing
in my crib...
Is it burnt crust?
WERNICK: That is Bea Arthur on the shirt.
I... God,
I hope not. Um...
REYNOLDS: Yup.
Whoa... Man, look,
if this is about that poker game.
That cost 10 grand.
I told Howie,
I told him that...
-I don't mind saying.
-WERNICK: Is that right?
Okay, uh, look,
just take whatever you want.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
REESE: Uh, is that right?
WERNICK: Who did we
have to license that from?
Thanks.
Is that Bea Arthur's estate
or is that Golden Girls?
REYNOLDS". That is exactly it.
Sir, before you do
anything to him,
It was the Bea Arthur's estate.
do you mind
if I get a big tip?
It was a donation to one of her charities,
(CHUCKLES)
Uh, Jeremy, is it?
which I think was wonderful
and totally worthwhile doing.
Umm-hmm.
Wade. Wade Wilson.
But as a producer,
I had to approve a $10,000....
That is a no go
on the tiperoo, Jer.
Which was just stupid at the time
because we were so desperate
to keep every penny on the screen
I'm not here for him.
I'm here for you.
and our movie
did not have a big budget at all.
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
But you can't have a Deadpool movie
without Bea Arthur appearing,
Okay, wow, dodged
a big-time bullet on that one.
Not out of the woods yet.
(GROANS)
so I felt like it was worth it.
You need to seriously ease up
on the bedazzling.
WERNICK: Oh, for sure.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
They're jeans,
not a chandelier.
P.S. I'm keeping your wallet.
You did kinda give it to me.
Okay, just look, man,
can I have my Sam's card...
I will shoot your fucking cat!
REESE: Those sunglasses
that, uh, Gavin's wearing right there
I don't really know what that means.
I don't have a cat.
end up on your face in the next scene,
Then whose kitty litter
did I just shit in?
and I think very few people
make that connection.
REYNOLDS: I don't think anybody... I know...
And I always cringe as I'm coming down
the stairs wearing them in the next scene
Anyhoo, tell me something...
what situation
isn't improved by pizza?
because I worry that people think
I just made a fashion choice
by selecting those glasses.
Do you happen to know
a Meghan Orflosky?
Getting that right? Orflosky?
Getting that right?
Orflosky?
REYNOLDS: "Orflosky?"
Orlovsky? Yeah? Good.
WERNICK: The, uh, pizza box
-is, uh, Feige's famous...
-(REYNOLDS LAUGHS)
Because she knows you.
-Kevin Feige?
-WERNICK: Kevin Feige.
Jeremy, I belong
to a group of guys
A little Easter egg to the head of Marvel.
who take a dime
to beat a fella down.
And little Meghan,
she's not made of money,
-The genius behind Marvel.
-REYNOLDS: That's true.
but lucky for her...
I got a soft spot.
RE ESE: But it does bear mentioning,
this is not a Marvel Studio movie.
But I'm a...
A stalker.
Threats hurt, Jer.
This is a Fox movie.
Though not nearly as badly
as serrated steel.
And a lot of people make that mistake
or make that assumption that this is...
REYNOLDS". I'm always shocked
how many people in the media
So keep away
from Meghan.
make that mistake, too.
You get a lot of that, too.
Yes, sir.
Cool?
Then we're done.
Wait. (CHUCKLES SLOWLY)
We are?
-And the media's never wrong, so...
-(REESE LAUGHS)
Yeah. We're totally done.
(LAUGHS)
You should've seen your face.
You should've
seen your face.
I didn't know what to do.
I was so scared.
REYNOLDS: That guy was great.
That guy was fantastic.
Soft spot, remember?
(WHIMPERS)
You even look
in her general direction again...
You even look in her
general direction again...
and you will learn in the worst of ways
that I have some hard spots too.
and you will learn
in the worst of ways
that I have
some hard spots too.
(REESE LAUGHING)
That came out wrong.
REYNOLDS". He had no idea
I was gonna kiss him here
and he reacted perfectly, I was very happy.
Or did it?
(WHIMPERING)
-Oh, there you go.
-(REYNOLDS AND REESE CHUCKLING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
WERNER. This was the final scene we shot
of the movie...
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
REYNOLDS: Of the whole film, yeah.
WERNICK: Yeah.
It was, uh...
REYNOLDS". And we said
it would never see the light of day.
-And here it is.
-WERNICK: And here we are.
Meghan?
Mmm... Meghan?
REYNOLDS". Mostly 'cause of those glasses
that nobody realizes are from...
REESE: I love your expression
when you look at them, though.
You've heard the last
of Jeremy. He's sorry.
Here, as you take them off.
No friggin' way.
REYNOLDS". Oh, it's so...
Thank God we found that take because, uh...
Ew! Yeah, there you go.
They're really horrible.
Should've brought
my roller blades.
Show these kids
how it's done.
(REYNOLDS CHUCKLES)
Oh. And that's why we do it.
But mostly the money.
Rollerblades for whatever reason
have always made me laugh.
Hey, think you could
fuck up my step-dad?
WERNICK: Always. That was a Ryan ad-lib.
I give a guy
a pavement facial,
Ryan is just a genius ad-libber, um,
it's because he's earned it.
Hey, wait!
a genius improviser and just...
REYNOLDS: (SINGSONG VOICE)
I can hear you.
You're my hero.
No-no-no-no. That I ain't!
No-no-no-no.
That I ain't!
REYNOLDS". We have a lot of fun.
We all had a lot of fun writing alts, though.
WADE: Nope. Never will be.
Like that was our favorite pastime
Oh. Fuck you, Wade.
on the set.
-WERNICK: Yeah.
I'm just a bad guy
who gets paid to fuck up worse guys.
I'm just a bad guy who gets
paid to fuck up worse guys.
WADE: Welcome to Sister Margaret's.
Welcome to Sister Margaret's.
It's like a job fair for mercenaries.
It's like a job fair
for mercenaries.
WERNICK: Sister Margaret's we shot,
that was, um...
Think of us as really
fucked up tooth fairies...
What bar in Vancouver was that, Ryan?
That was a...
except we knock out the teeth
and take the cash.
You'd best hope we never see
your name on a gold card.
REYNOLDS". That was
The Cobalt bar in Vancouver.
WERNER The Cobalt.
Buck! Liefeld...
REYNOLDS". A bar, when I was a kid,
you would never go within 3,000 feet of.
BUCK: Hey, Wade!
And now is just like hipster central.
Wade Wilson,
patron saint of the pitiful.
WERNICK: Is it? Because it felt like
What can I do for you?
-you still wouldn't go within 3,000 feet.
-(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
I'd love a Blow Job.
Oh, God, me too.
Yeah, it has its night.
The drink, moose knuckle.
But first...
A specific night
where it's sort of hipster central,
but, yeah, otherwise it's generally kind of...
Hey, and I ain't taking
any babysitting money, all right?
Make sure that gets back to Ms...
Make sure
that gets back to Ms...
REESE: I wouldn't go within 3,000 feet
of hipster central, to be honest.
Orlovsky.
Yeah, her.
REYNOLDS: Well, that's true, yeah.
You sure?
Hmm.
You know, for a mere,
you we pretty warm-brooded.
You know, for a merc,
you're pretty warm-blooded.
I bet you let the kid off easy, too.
I bet you let
the kid off easy, too.
REESE: T.J. Miller. Force of nature.
REYNOLDS: Love T.J. Miller.
Oh, he's not a bad kid, Weas.
Just a little light stalking.
I was way worse than him
when I was his age.
I was traveling to exotic places...
I was traveling
to exotic places...
REYNOLDS: T.J. Miller is
one of those guys that can...
Baghdad, Mogadishu,
Jacksonville,
He can't not improvise. Like, you can't...
meeting new and exciting
people. And then, uh...
Killing them. Yeah,
I've seen your Instagram.
It's like a fish in water.
He just has to fuck around.
So what was Special Forces doing
in Jacksonville, anyway?
And it's great.
That's classified.
And at least this is the kind of film where
we leave a lot of room to do that so...
(WHISPERS) They have
a wonderful TGI Fridays.
All right,
Kahlua, Baileys and...
WEASEL: ...whipped cream.
whipped cream.
I give you a Blow Job.
Why do you make me make that?
Why do you
make me make that?
Kelly, Kelly, Kelly...
Take that over to Buck, please,
and tell him it's from Boothe.
Take that over
to Buck please,
Little foreplay.
and tell him it's from Boothe.
Remind me what good will come of this?
Remind me what good
will come of this?
I don't take the shits.
I just disturb them.
-BUCK: Boothe!
-Oh!
BUCK: Boothe!
Oh!
-Easy, man.
-Hold up! Hold up!
Easy, man.
Hold up! Hold up!
What you want?
-(GRUNTS)
-(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(GRUNTS)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
-Cheers. To your health.
-WEASEL: Fuck you.
Cheers. To your health.
WEASEL: Fuck you.
BOOTHE: Come here, you fat fuck!
BOOTHE: Come here,
you fat fuck!
That's a new stool.
(ALL CLAMORING)
BUCK: Stay the fuck down.
(GROANS)
MAN: Whoa! Took his ass out!
WEASEL: All right, move.
Move, move, move.
Buck, go rest.
REESE: Now, originally we had...
MAN: Boothe got hit
then went down.
You had bet on Alex Trebek
in the dead pool right?
-That was who you decided...
-REYNOLDS: I bet on Alex Trebek.
Uh, I said it because Alejandro 's
favorite color is cocaine.
Yeah, he's still breathing.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Nobody wins today.
Nice try, Wade.
You got me. I picked Boothe
in the dead pool. Who did you pick?
You got me.
I picked Boothe in the dead pool.
Who did you pick?
Yeah, Wade, about that, um...
Yeah, Wade,
about that, um...
No.
You did not bet on me to die.
You did not bet
on me to die.
You bet on me to die.
REYNOLDS: Is anybody dead on
the dead pool, now? That would be awful.
You bet on me to die. Wow!
REESE: That would be awful.
REYNOLDS: I hope that's not the case.
Motherfucker, you're
the world's worst friend.
Well, joke's on you.
I'm living to 102.
WERNER. No, I don't think it is the case.
But who's up on that board? It's...
And then dying.
Like the city of Detroit.
REYNOLDS: You got everybody up there.
WERNICK: There's some great ones.
I'm sorry. I just...
I wanted to win money.
REYNOLDS". Bill Cosby, you got Tim Miller.
I never win anything.
Whatever.
(CHUCKLES) You got me.
Soldiers of fortune,
drinks on me!
WERNICK: Yeah, Ryan Reynolds.
(ALL CHEERING)
REYNOLDS". Yeah, Ryan Reynolds
is up there.
Domestic, nothing imported.
There's a shit ton of...
WERNICK: Justin Bieber's up there.
REYNOLDS: Great ones.
-Justin Bieber wasn't initially one of the...
-WERNICK: Oh, yes.
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa...
...names I had on the dead pool,
Baby, are you sure you wanna
shoot your whole wad?
or one of the guys I had picked
for the dead pool.
Uh... Tight.
-Vanessa.
-Wade.
Vanessa.
Wade.
WERNER When we were trying
to get the movie made,
What's a nice place like you
doing in a girl like this?
we were doing everything and anything,
and actually there was a computer program
I'd hit that.
Buck, you best
apologize before...
that you could, uh...
It was like an animated computer program,
(GASPS)
Yeah, that.
Say the magic words,
Fat Gandalf.
where the voice
was a computer-generated voice
I'm sorry.
Breathe through the nose.
I don't have a filter
between my brain and my...
and you could punch in dialogue
Let go. Okay.
Hey, oh, oh, oh...
and the computer would spit out the voice
matched to the animated characters.
Hakuna his tatas.
He's sorry.
I'm working on it.
Get out of here.
Go. Go cast a spell.
REYNOLDS: I loved that.
Hey. Hands off
the merchandise.
WERNICK: And we made one...
REYNOLDS: Is that available somewhere?
WERNER I tried to pull it back up
and I couldn't. They had gotten rid of it.
Merchandise? Huh...
So you, uh...
REYNOLDS: Damn.
WERNICK: It didn't exist anymore.
REESE: We made one
for this particular scene.
bump fuzzies for money?
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Yep.
Rough childhood?
I always loved this...
Rougher than yours.
Daddy left before
I was born.
This is just you guys being geniuses.
Daddy left before
I was conceived.
I love this dialogue here,
between the both of us.
Ever had a cigarette
put out on your skin?
Where else do you
put one out?
I was molested.
Me too. Uncle.
REYNOLDS: Morena was such a sport.
Uncles. They took turns.
She loves working blue.
I watched my own
birthday party
through the keyhole
of a locked closet...
Which also happens to be my...
which also happens to be my...
Your bedroom. Lucky.
I slept in a dishwasher box.
REYNOLDS". She has
a wonderful potty mouth.
You had a dishwasher.
(GASPS) You had a dishwasher.
I didn't even know sleep.
It was pretty much 24/7 ball gags,
brownie mix and clown porn.
It was pretty much
24/7 ball gags,
brownie mix and clown porn.
(LAUGHS)
REESE: Boy, I'm just afraid of that word,
"clown porn," that just sounds terrifying.
Who would do such a thing?
REYNOLDS: Clown porn?
REESE: Yeah.
REYNOLDS". You'd be shocked.
It's actually not bad.
Hopefully you, later tonight?
(REESE LAUGHS)
Hey, what can I get for,
uh, $275 and a...
WERNICK: Did they shave a little notch
into your eyebrow, Ryan?
REYNOLDS". You only
realized that just now?
WERNICK: I just now realized that.
a Yogurtland rewards card?
REYNOLDS: Of course, there's scars
all over my head and my face.
Baby, about 48 minutes of
whatever the fuck you want.
And we wanted to give Wade a kind of look
of as though he had
sort of a history of violence.
And a low-fat dessert.
And so there's scars all over.
You could see the side of my head,
there's one.
One that runs through my eyebrow.
And that's all the great Bill Corso,
who's just a genius makeup artist,
Did she just put a gift card
in your mouth?
who also did our scarring effect
on Deadpool's face.
It's time to put
balls in holes.
-He's, uh...
-WERNICK: Oh, he's brilliant.
You said whatever I want.
REYNOLDS". He did Foxcatcher
and a few other movies that are just...
I get it.
Lemony Snicket's. Incredible makeup work.
You love skee ball.
Apparently more than
you love vagina.
WERNICK: Tireless, too. On set
at the crack of dawn all the way through.
That's a tough call.
(SCOFFS)
(STUTTERS) I just wanna get to
know the real you, you know.
Not the short-shorted,
two-dimensional
REYNOLDS: Yeah, just a great attitude.
Great work.
sex object
peddled by Hollywood.
VANESSA: Balls in holes.
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
REESE: The skee ball scene
was not in the original script
Balls in holes.
and it was added to give a little bit more
of a sense of connection
Prepare to lose tragically.
Bring it, big man.
Okay.
and romantic development
-between these two characters...
-REYNOLDS: Mmm-hmm.
(MOCKING SCOOBY-DOO)
Uh-oh.
...so that their relationship wasn't
too based just on sex.
Uh-oh.
The limited edition
Voltron: Defender of
the Universe ring, por favor.
And I think it captures Wade's
kind of immature childish spirit.
Okay. Here we go.
I think one of the most important
characteristics of Deadpool
Had my eye on
this sucker for a while.
is his childish nature.
And I will take
the pencil eraser.
REYNOLDS". Yeah, he really
sort of represents
BOY: Okay.
a huge part of the population
that are adult geeks.
You are now the protector
of the planet Arus.
I love that. I love that about him.
And you can erase stuff...
written in pencil.
He worships the Voltron Ring.
M'lady?
WERNICK: My children were in this scene
Well, I hate to
break it to you...
but your 48 minutes
are up.
and ended up
on the cutting room floor, actually.
REYNOLDS: Where they belong.
WERNICK: Where they belong.
Hey, how many more minutes
can I get for this?
-(LAUGHS)
-REYNOLDS: Where they belong.
FYI, five mini lion-bots
come together
REESE: If their performances
had been better...
REYNOLDS". No nepotism
on this film, I'm sorry.
to form one super-bot, so...
(REESE CHUCKLES)
Five mini lion-bots?
Three minutes.
WERNER Voltron, uh...
Deal.
Rhett, talk about the Voltron thing
because that was a little bit of a late add.
What do we do with the remaining
two minutes, 37 seconds?
Cuddle?
REESE: Well, I think, again,
it was just getting at that nerd...
(MOANING)
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay, we gotta stop talking about Voltron
and start talking about this.
How long can you
keep this up?
Because this was probably the toughest
particular sequence in the movie.
All year?
(CHUCKLES)
(CONTINUES MOANING)
REYNOLDS: How is it that we spent
more time on this fucking sequence
than any other sequence in the film,
I think?
Happy Valentine's Day.
REESE: It was just so difficult to
choreograph and design jokes around and...
WERNICK: Get the right tone.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Happy Chinese New Year.
International Women's Day coming up.
Year of the Dog.
That's one of our favorites.
WERNER Which is, what,
March 8th, Rhett?
(EXHALES)
REYNOLDS: March 8th,
International Women's Day.
Relax.
WERNICK". March 8th, yeah.
And Happy
International Women's Day.
REYNOLDS". Also my brother's birthday
and Alanis Morissette Day.
WERNER Mmm.
(WHIP CRACKS)
-(CHUCKLES) All March 8th?
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
(GROANS) No. No. No.
-I know.
-WERNICK: Is that right?
REYNOLDS: I know my, uh...
WERNICK: You know your March 8th's.
REYNOLDS: We know our holidays now,
after this fucking movie.
Happy Lent.
We actually had an alt here,
which was Happy Alanis Morissette Day,
(MOANING)
but we didn't use it.
Ow, ow.
-Wade?
-Sorry.
Wade?
Sorry.
REESE: We had to line up all the holidays
Happy Halloween.
so that they occurred in the correct
chronological order around the year,
Happy Halloween.
(LAUGHS)
which was difficult.
(CONTINUES MOANING)
REYNOLDS: We could have just shot a scene
where two people fuck for five minutes
that might have been easier.
Happy Thanksgiving.
WERNICK: Surely easier.
REYNOLDS: But we do love our
Deadpool audience, so...
I love you.
If your left leg is Thanksgiving...
If your left leg
is Thanksgiving...
and your right leg is Christmas...
and your right leg
is Christmas...
REYNOLDS". Angus Strathie was
our costume designer,
can I visit you
between the holidays?
who found all these horrific sweaters.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh!
That sweater is terrible.
(LAUGHS)
But red looks good on you.
Red's your color.
REYNOLDS". This is just
the worst one I chose.
Brings out the bloodshot
in your eyes.
You can imagine what was available.
Listen,
I've been thinking...
Really?
...about why we're so good together.
...about why we're
so good together.
Why's that?
Well, your crazy matches my crazy.
Big time.
Well, your crazy matches
my crazy. Big time.
Hmm. (CHUCKLES)
And, uh, we're like two jigsaw pieces,
you know, the weird curvy edges...
And, uh, we're like
two jigsaw pieces,
you know,
the weird curvy edges...
You put them together
and you can see the picture on top.
You put them together and you
can see the picture on top.
Right.
Wade...
there's something I've been
meaning to ask you.
But only because you haven't
gotten around to asking me.
Will you, um...
Will you, uh...
-stick it in my...
-Marry me?
stick it in my...
Marry me?
(REYNOLDS CHUCKLES)
WERNICK: My brother actually
proposed to his wife with a ring pop.
Uh... Jinx?
Huh.
Where were you
hiding that?
REYNOLDS: (LAUGHS)
With a ring pop, really?
Nowhere.
WERNER Yeah.
REESE: ls that true?
WERNICK: Yes.
They say one month's salary.
So, uh...
REYNOLDS: Was it hiding up
his asshole, as well?
You mean?
WERNICK: (LAUGHS) I will have to ask him.
REYNOLDS: Was he...
I do.
That's my line.
Please do, I would love to...
I love you, Wade Wilson.
You're supposed to...
So that's a...
-Yes!
-Whoo!
Yes!
Whoo!
REYNOLDS: There we go.
Yes!
(LAUGHS)
I feel just like a little girl.
I feel just like
a little girl.
-(CHUCKLES)
-(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
What if I just held on and never let go?
What if I just held on
and never let go?
Just ride a bitch's back,
like Yoda on Luke.
Oh, Star Wars jokes.
Empire.
Jesus Christ.
It's like I...
WERNICK: Interestingly, this movie
is many things and...
It's like I made you
in a computer.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
Mmm.
The beating heart of it is the love story
between these two characters.
Hey.
Perfect.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
REYNOLDS". Yeah, we kind of made a joke
about that in the marketing,
Let's see.
All right, wee break.
but it really, actually is sort of true.
It does kind of anchor everything.
Shake it, yeah.
You know, it's what fuels
the revenge story in the film.
(SIGHS)
WERNICK: It is a fucked-up
romantic comedy.
WADE: Here's the thing.
Life is an endless series
of train-wrecks...
Again, it's many things,
but that is one thing it is.
with only brief,
commercial-like breaks of happiness.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
This had been the ultimate
commercial break.
God bless it, though.
WERNER Oh, look at that. Look at that.
(TOILET FLUSHING)
(SIGHS)
That's years of hard work right there...
Which meant
it was time to return
-(REYNOLDS LAUGHS)
-...in the gym.
to our regularly
scheduled program.
REESE: And a lot of salmon.
REYNOLDS". Yeah, there's a lot of salmon
I ate for this movie.
What the...
(THUDS)
Oh, my God. Wade?
-And steamed vegetables.
REESE: Whole rivers.
Rivers full of salmon.
REYNOLDS". Oh, I just single-handedly
-depleted the world's salmon supply.
-(REESE CHUCKLES)
You're clowning.
You're not clowning?
I sense clowns.
WERNER This was the first scene
we shot of the movie.
People react to news of
late-stage cancer differently.
REYNOLDS: Oh, my God. You're right.
WERNICK: Day one.
There are certainly options
we can look into.
REYNOLDS: I always think it's Blind AI,
but this was... No, this was day minus one.
New drugs are being
developed every day.
-This was an off-the-record day.
-WERNICK: Yeah.
REYNOLDS". We shot this in pre-production
just because we... The movie...
So what do we do?
We had basically $50
to make a $500 movie, let's say.
Surely there is
something we can do.
My uncle Ivan was diagnosed
with thyroid cancer...
And so we had to do
a lot of cheating and fudging
and there were all these new
experimental drugs from Germany.
and one of them
was shooting this day in advance.
WADE: Vanessa's already
working on Plan A, B,
So it was kind of off-the-books.
all the way through Z.
WERNER It was a 48-day shoot,
which is, for a movie like this, tiny.
Me? I'm memorizing
the details of her face.
REYNOLDS: It's insane.
WERNICK: Tiny.
Like it's the first time
I'm seeing it.
REYNOLDS". It's like a little independent film
shooting schedule so, yeah.
Or the last.
DOCTOR: Mr. Wilson...
WERNICK: Most movies
of this scope and scale,
Mr. Wilson?
Take your time
to process this.
really, that's second unit days,
they have 48 days.
It's important not to
do anything rash.
REYNOLDS: I'll invoke Green Lantern
for a second time.
Green Lantern, just to give
you a perspective, was an 89-day shoot.
(WADE GRUNTS)
-And this was 48.
-WERNICK: So we were lean and mean.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
(SIGHS LOUDLY)
Now, if I were
a 200-pound sack
WERNICK: And really
the mother of invention, I feel like.
It just forced us to look at things
in a different way.
of assholes named Francis,
where would I hide?
(MOTORBIKE REVVING)
And attack things.
REYNOLDS: Necessity is truly
invention 's mama.
Oh.
And it, yeah...
It made us focus on character
so much more than anything else.
(ENGINE ROARING)
(GUN FIRING)
But we still got to do some fun stuff.
-Like that.
-REESE: Yeah.
I mean, among the scenes
we had to cut for budget,
we did have a motorcycle chase here,
(FRANCIS GRUNTS)
where Deadpool was chasing Ajax
on a motorcycle.
REYNOLDS". I miss that sequence,
though. That would have been fun.
WADE: A hush falls
over the crowd
WERNICK: I loved that, too.
as rookie sensation
Wade W. Wilson...
out of Regina, Saskatchewan,
lines up the shot.
REYNOLDS". Regina, Saskatchewan.
That joke probably only makes
Canadians laugh,
but it makes me laugh.
His form looks good.
Oh, and that is why Regina rhymes with fun.
Oh!
And that's why Regina
rhymes with fun.
WERNER. Which, Ryan, tell us the story.
You were a child...
Ladies and gentlemen,
what you're witnessing...
REYNOLDS". No, I was not,
I wish I was a child.
is sweet dick-kicking revenge.
I was about 25 years old,
and I was in Regina, Saskatchewan.
Oh! Giving him the business.
And I got into a lot of trouble because I...
Incoming!
This is taking unsportsmanlike
conduct to a whole new level!
I messed with a sign and changed it.
I just actually put another sign over it,
(FRANCIS GROANS)
so I didn't actually
vandalize public property,
but I put another sign over it that said,
"Welcome to Regina,
Looking good, Francis.
Well rested.
-"which rhymes with fun."
-(WERNICK CHUCKLES)
Like you've been pitching,
not catching.
REYNOLDS: And I got into a lot of trouble
for that, but something good came out of it.
Ringing any bells? No?
It's now in the Deadpool movie, so...
How about now?
WERNICK: That's all computer-generated
right there.
Ryan, obviously, wasn't in the scarred
makeup under the mask.
(CHUCKLES SLOWLY)
Wade fucking Wilson.
REYNOLDS: I sure wasn't.
WERNICK: When he was in the mask,
that was...
FRANCIS: Well,
hello, gorgeous.
WADE: Yeah, like I got bit
by a radioactive Shar-Pei.
REESE: But something you just said,
where you said, "It makes me laugh, "
Yeah. And whose fault
is that, huh, Francis?
I think that's an important point
because so much
of the comedy in this movie,
Yeah, time to undo what
you did to this butterface.
Please,
you should thank me.
we had to rely on our guts and say,
"Well, does it make us laugh?"
Apparently,
I made you immortal.
I'm actually
quite jealous.
And we took that approach,
Yeah, but this ain't
a life worth living, is it?
if it's making us laugh,
perhaps it will make others laugh.
And I think that held us
in pretty good stead.
Now, I'm about
to do to you
REYNOLDS: I do, too. We had so...
what Limp Bizkit did to
music in the late 90s.
This is another one that just made us laugh
and people seem to like it.
(METAL CLANKS)
Dad?
(REYNOLDS LAUGHS)
It's T.J. Miller's favorite joke.
WADE: I think we can all agree that shit just
went sideways in the most colossal way.
WADE: I think we can all agree
that shit just went sideways
in the most colossal way.
REYNOLDS: There's our
Wolverine X-Men Origins reference.
Well, maybe not the most.
WADE: Uh... This is
my most prized possession.
I think, maybe our...
(CHUCKLES) We only make two or three
references to it in the movie,
VANESSA: Wham?
No, no, no. Wham!
but that's one of them.
Make It Big is the album that George
and Andy earned the exclamation point.
WERNER You know what people don't get
is the one where,
"I'm gonna sew
your pretty little mouth shut."
REYNOLDS". And they say,
"I wouldn't do that."
So, am I supposed
to just smile
WERNICK "Oh, I wouldn't do that."
and wave you out the door?
-People don't click into that as much.
-REYNOLDS: I don't think they realize, yeah.
Think of it like
spring cleaning.
Only if spring
was death.
WERNICK: But it's, on
second viewing maybe, yeah.
God, if I had a nickel
for every time
REESE: Yeah.
WERNER Or third viewing.
I spanked it to
Bernadette Peters.
REESE: Yeah, I do think the movie will have
a lot of second and third viewing
Sounds like you do.
(COINS JINGLING)
Bernadette is not
going anywhere,
surprises for people
who miss things the first time.
because you're not
going anywhere.
REYNOLDS". Yeah, there's lots of jokes
that you miss.
Drink.
REESE: Pretty rich in detail.
You're right.
Cancer is only in my liver,
REYNOLDS: I ran into Bernadette Peters,
which is just a weird thing to say,
lungs, prostate, and brain.
All things I can
live without.
Ha.
um, in New York City
maybe four months ago.
You belong here
at home.
Surrounded by
your Voltron
And she mentioned this scene
because she had to give her permission
and your Bernadette,
and your me.
for us to use her name.
Listen, we both know
that cancer is a shit-show.
And she was very flattered
and very sweet about it.
Like, a Yakov-Smirnoff-
opening-for-the
WERNICK". In our start gifts,
there was a signed Bernadette Peters
Spin-Doctors-at-the-
Iowa-State-Fair shit-show.
-framed 8x10 of her...
-REYNOLDS: Mmm.
And under no circumstances
will I take you to that show.
...which I actually think Simon Kinberg
forged her signature.
REYNOLDS: I believe he did.
I want you to remember me.
I found out for a fact that indeed,
Simon Kinberg
forged Bernadette Peters' signature,
Not the ghost
of Christmas me.
Well, I wanna remember us.
-which is probably illegal.
-WERNICK: I think so.
Bernadette, if you're out there,
I swear to God, I will
find you in the next life...
-we would love an original signed...
-REYNOLDS: Simon Kinberg.
and I'm gonna boom-box
Careless Whisper outside your window.
-His number is 310-874...
-(WERNICK LAUGHS)
Wham!
No one is boom-boxing shit. Okay?
No one is boom-boxing shit.
Okay?
We can fight this.
WERNICK: Rhett, talk about
some of the obscure references
We can fight this.
to Yakov Smirnoff and, you know...
REESE: Well, I think we always felt that
Besides, I just
realized something.
You win.
Your life is officially
not every reference had to make sense
for every audience member.
way more fucked up
than mine.
So we freed ourselves
and allowed ourselves occasionally
(WADE CHUCKLES)
to make references that we thought
only a few people would get.
I love you.
I mean, when you're talking about
Ronnie Milsap...
REYNOLDS: Oh, my God.
...in a movie that's intended
for 17 to 34-year-olds,
(MUSIC PLAYING)
you're gonna go over some heads.
But we were committed to the idea
that Deadpool has a deep understanding
Wade.
-and memory for pop culture.
-WERNICK: Yeah.
Weas.
REESE: And that we just had to honor that.
You look like you need
a Blow Job and a shower.
REYNOLDS: But we all kind Of do.
All three of us together are sort of...
Though courtesy calls
for the latter first.
-We love pop culture.
REESE: Yes.
How about three shots
of Patron?
REYNOLDS". I'm not saying that we
always understand it, but we love it.
Or how about Triticum aestivum,
wheatgrass.
We make a Cocoon joke in the movie.
I mean, that was fun. I love that.
Excellent for
the immune system.
Jesus Christ.
You sound like Vanessa.
WADE: Here, check it out.
Here, check it out.
WERNICK: Yeah. Usually they say,
pop culture, you have to...
She's sending away for all these
colorful clinic brochures.
Has to be a timeless reference
so that doesn't date the movie,
I'm sure they're
all FDA approved.
but again, as Rhett was saying,
the beauty of Deadpool is,
Chechnya. Isn't that where
you go to get cancer?
you can make
those obscure references for comedy.
You got China
and Central Mexico.
REYNOLDS; Oh, yeah.
WERNICK: And it Still works
You know how they
say "cancer" in Spanish?
and almost even enhances the movie
in such a way that...
No.
El Cancer.
Oh.
REYNOLDS". Totally, yeah.
I could have
guessed that.
Look how happy you look here.
Look how happy
you look here.
REYNOLDS: Paul, was that your joke?
Mind if I keep this?
Put it up,
The "Chechnya,
isn't that where you go to get cancer?"
so I can remember
when you looked alive.
WERNICK: Yeah.
REYNOLDS: I love that.
At least now I'm gonna
win the dead pool.
WERNICK: We added that in,
in ADR, actually.
REYNOLDS: (LAUGHS) Yeah.
Now that you're gonna die
tragically of cancer.
It used to be "Chechnya.
-"I hear that's nice this time of never. "
-WERNICK: Yeah.
I got it, Weas. Thanks.
REESE: Which is also fun.
WERNICK AND REYNOLDS: Also fun, yeah.
Oh.
And, uh, that guy over there
came in looking for you.
REESE: And we were setting up
a sequence in the movie
Real Grim Reaper type.
that will likely be in the deleted scenes
I don't know.
Might further the plot.
where Wade goes on a world tour
to get his cancer cured.
REYNOLDS". Oh, God, yeah.
That was good stuff.
REESE: And ultimately ends up
in Guadalajara, Mexico,
Boothe.
and meets a quack doctor
who's taking advantage of cancer victims
Wade.
and ends up killing him
and feels guilty about it.
(WADE SIGHS)
There's a whole sequence
we ended up taking out of the movie
Mr. Wilson.
How can I help you?
after much long discussion.
Besides luring children
into a panel van.
And hopefully you'll find it
in the deleted scenes.
REYNOLDS; Yeah.
REESE: And if not... (CLICKS TONGUE)
I understand you've recently
been diagnosed with terminal cancer.
-... you're SOL.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Stalker alert.
This is Jed Rees.
It's my job.
Recruitment.
Local Vancouver actor,
guy I've known for maybe 20 years.
I'm sorry you've had
such a tough go.
Great actor, fun, game for anything.
But you're a fighter.
Special Forces.
41 confirmed kills.
WERNICK: Galaxy Quest.
REESE: Yeah, he played the good alien
in Galaxy Quest.
One every seven weeks.
Same rate most folks
get a haircut. Hmm...
REYNOLDS". He had fun on DeadpooL
He was very sad that we killed him
It's to wash
the taste out.
It's tough to forget
being so impressive.
'cause he was hoping to be in the sequel.
WERNER And interestingly, Agent Smith,
obviously a nod to, um...
And now you
spend your days
sticking up for
the little people...
People change.
What do you want?
REESE: The Matrix. Yeah.
WERNICK The Matrix.
I represent an organization
that may be able to help.
Although some people
think his name is Agent Smith.
REYNOLDS: They just think his name
is Agent Smith.
What if I told you
we can cure your cancer?
REESE: Yeah, and that was
an improv of yours, wasn't it, Ryan?
The Agent Smith thing?
It made me laugh in the moment.
And what's more, give you abilities
most men only dream of?
REYNOLDS". I think that was actually
your guys' writing. I think so.
(STAMMERING) I made
the horrible pedophile jokes,
I'd say that you sound
like an infomercial,
I think, at the end of the scene, but...
but not a good one,
like Slap Chop.
REESE: So funny.
More Shake Weight-y.
REYNOLDS". Agent Smith was
you guys, though, which I love, yeah.
The world needs
extraordinary soldiers.
WERNICK: Have you seen the GIF or "JlF,"
I'm not sure... That's going around?
We won't just
make you better.
We will make you
better than better.
It's you doing the Shake Weight
back and forth.
REYNOLDS: Oh, yeah. (CHUCKLES)
WERNICK: It's really funny.
A superhero.
REYNOLDS". I have. I don't know...
I'm not sure how I feel about it.
Look, Agent Smith,
-WERNICK (LAUGHS) I love it.
-(REYNOLDS AND REESE LAUGH)
I tried the hero business
and it left a mark.
WERNER Made me laugh.
But if I ever hit "fuck it,"
I'll look you up.
REYNOLDS". Can you imagine, we're gonna
have to start tailoring performances
Oh, um...
to whether or not they'll be turned
into GIFs?
Shit. We're within
500 yards of a school,
WERNICK Yeah.
so you may wanna...
REYNOLDS: IS it "JIF" or "GIF?"
WERNICK: I think it's "GIF."
REYNOLDS: I thought we're pop culture...
-WERNICK: I know.
-...savvy in some way, but, no.
His drink's on him.
I think it's "GIF. "
WEASEL: What did he say?
(THUNDERCLAP)
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
REESE: I hate seeing that business card
with the "555" on it...
-REYNOLDS: Fuck.
-...that always takes me out of the movie.
REYNOLDS: It just drove us all crazy.
WERNICK: It's actually Ryan's
cellphone number, isn't it?
(SNIFFLES)
REYNOLDS". Yes.
Do give it a shout, give it a try.
WERNICK AND REESE: Call it.
WERNICK: It doesn't even need
an area code.
REYNOLDS: No.
WERNICK: You just do the seven numbers.
REYNOLDS: 555...
I can't believe we have that in there
and we don't even make a joke about it.
VANESSA: Hey, what's going on?
Hey. Sorry.
(SNIFFLES) Hey. Sorry.
REYNOLDS: This is, uh...
...a joke from Rhett and Paul,
which is one of my favorites.
I had a Liam Neeson
nightmare.
I dreamt I kidnapped
his daughter
and he just
wasn't having it.
REESE". I think we were at the front half of it
and then this was your improvised line
about him being a bad parent
-which made us laugh so hard.
-REYNOLDS: Oh, God.
Hey, uh, they've made
three of those movies.
At some point you have to wonder
if he's just a bad parent.
At some point you have
to wonder if he's just a bad parent.
Hmm.
REYNOLDS". I've always liked that Deadpool,
or Wade Wilson in that moment,
he's obviously got
his mind on something else
and he's in this tragic moment,
but he still keeps up appearances.
Sort of shows how his mind works.
He's still making these jokes,
these random jokes.
He's even phoning them in,
but it's still a lot of fun.
WADE: The worst part about cancer
isn't what it does to you...
WERNICK: Yeah, it's really, you know...
but what it does to
the people you love.
Wade Wilson, Deadpool's such a
complex character
Who knew if this guy
could save my life...
that really, you know,
but I knew there was only one
way that I could save hers.
you look at his life
and there's so much tragedy in it.
(DOOR CLOSES)
And he hides behind that tragedy.
The comedy is what masks
the tragedy of his life.
Isn't that what
superheroes do?
And I feel that it really
makes him relatable
(CARS HONKING)
in a way that he's struggling with things
(PHONE RINGING)
that everybody in real life struggles with
and deals with it in his own particular way.
WADE: Okay. Let's pro-con
this superhero thing.
REYNOLDS: Mmm-hmm.
(THUDS)
Ow.
WADE: Pro: They pull down a gaggle of ass.
Pro: They pull down
a gaggle of ass.
Local dry cleaning discounts.
Lucrative film deals...
WERNICK: Here comes fourth wall.
Lucrative film deals,
both origin stories
Another fourth wall moment.
and larger ensemble
team movies.
Ryan, talk about Deadpool
and fourth wall and the comics.
Con: They're all lame-ass
teacher's pets.
REYNOLDS: Well, you can't have Deadpool
without him breaking the fourth wall.
You know,
I can hear you.
I wasn't talking to you.
I was talking to them.
That was the first thing that we all,
sort of, agreed upon years and years ago.
Stay right here.
COLOSSUS: You've been
warned before, Deadpool.
We tried to do as much of it
as made sense in the filming,
This is a shameful and
reckless use of your powers.
and actually, by the end of the movie,
we went back to camera
and shot a few extra ones
You will both
be coming with us.
because we just felt like
we didn't have enough.
WADE: Look, Colossus,
I don't have time for
the goody two-shoes
bullshit right now!
-I love breaking the fourth wall.
-WERNICK: And that's really...
And you are?
It's really a signature of Deadpool
and was in the comics
-from the very start.
-REYNOLDS: Very much.
Negasonic Teenage Warhead.
Negasonic Teenage...
What the shit?
WERNER. And not only fourth wall
in that he's addressing the camera,
That's the coolest name ever!
but he's also very aware
that he's in a movie
So, what, you're like,
uh, his sidekick?
No. Trainee.
and that he's a superhero, right, Rhett?
Let me guess.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
REESE: Yeah.
X-Men left you behind
on what? Shit detail?
Well, or not a superhero.
What does that make you?
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
WERNICK: Yeah.
Pretending you're not here,
Negasonic Teenage Warhead.
REESE: As the case may be, but, yes.
Can we trade names?
Can we go?
(FRANCIS GROANS)
Look! I'm a teenage girl.
WADE: Look!
I'm a teenage girl.
WERNICK: Negasonic Teenage Warhead.
I'd rather be
anywhere than here.
I'm all about
long sullen silences...
Rhett, talk about, um,
how we stumbled onto her and...
followed by mean comments,
followed by more silences.
So what's it gonna be, huh?
Long sullen silence...
REESE: Well, Tim, our director, wanted
some extra superheroes in the movie,
or mean comment? Go on.
particularly on the X-Men side.
You got me in a box here.
Colossus was already in there.
Aha!
We can't allow this,
Deadpool.
But we thought a trainee might be fun.
Please, come quietly.
You big chrome
cock-gobbler!
Tim gave us this list
of potential minor characters to use,
COLOSSUS: That's not nice.
You're really gonna
fuck this up for me?
Trust me, that wheezing bag
of dick-tips has it coming.
and Negasonic was on the list
and we just fell in love with the name.
We said, "Who cares
what she's like necessarily,
He's pure evil.
"but that name is just priceless."
Besides...
Nobody's getting hurt.
So we built the character around the name.
(THUDS)
That guy was already up there
when I got here.
WERNICK: Ryan Reynolds' ad-lib genius,
right there.
Wade, you are
better than this.
(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
Join us.
Use your powers for good.
Well.
WERNER Uh, and NTW, her power,
she did not, in the comics,
WADE: Heads up.
Be a superhero.
WADE: Listen!
The day I decide to become a
crime-fighting shit-swizzler...
she doesn't have the explosive power
that she has in our movie.
who rooms with a bunch of other little
whiners at the Neverland mansion...
And for us to have added
that power to her resume,
of some creepy, old, bald,
Heaven's Gate-looking motherfucker...
on that day...
we had to ask Marvel for permission.
I'll send your shiny,
happy ass a friend request.
But until then,
I'mma do what I came here to do.
But until then, I'mma do
what I came here to do.
Either that or slap the bitch outta you!
Either that or slap
the bitch outta you!
-COLOSSUS: Wade...
-Hey.
COLOSSUS: Wade...
Hey.
Zip it, Sinéad!
Zip it, Sinead!
Hey, douche-pool!
And I hope you're watching...
And I hope
you're watching...
(MOTORBIKE REVVING)
(GASPS LOUDLY)
Quite unfortunate.
RE ESE: Colossus is a tremendous piece
of CG.
That does it!
I mean, he's...
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
(METAL CLANKS)
RE ESE: Just so impressive and I think
much better than he has been
Oh!
(GROANS) Canada!
in earlier incarnations.
REYNOLDS". Well, he's certainly
a faithful adaptation
That's not good.
-of Colossus now, so.
REESE: Very much.
COLOSSUS: Wade, please.
WADE: Cock shot!
(GROANS)
WERNICK'. And really, uh,
it's an actor in a mo-cap suit. Andre...
Oh, your poor wife.
You really should stop.
(GROANING)
REYNOLDS". Yeah.
Very hard to pronounce last name.
French Canadian name.
Tricoteux. Yeah.
All the dinosaurs
feared the T. rex.
But, great. Yeah, great actor.
(WADE SCREAMS)
WERNICK: So a lot of different pieces
went in to make Colossus.
(LAUGHS)
WADE: I promise this gets
worse for you, big boy!
Obviously, you have Andre,
who was on set in...
This is embarrassing.
(GROANS)
Please, stay down.
Who was, what, about a 6'5" giant,
WADE: You ever hear of the one-legged
man in the ass-kicking contest?
-who wore platform boots...
-REYNOLDS: Mmm-hmm.
Do you have
off switch?
Yeah, it's right next
to the prostate.
...to make himself about 6'8".
Or is that the on switch?
Enough!
(GLASS SHATTERS)
REYNOLDS: No, we had him...
He was about 7'5".
(LAUGHS)
WERNICK: IS that right?
REYNOLDS: ls, I think, the height
(GROANING)
that we ended up keeping Colossus.
REESE: We had that little tennis ball
on top of his head.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, to get him even higher.
REESE: It was like a Teletubby.
COLOSSUS: Let us go talk
to the Professor.
WERNER And then there was
a facial capture
McAvoy or Stewart?
These timelines
are so confusing.
of another actor I don't know.
"Dead or alive,
you're coming with me!"
-Do you know who that actor was?
REESE: I'm not sure.
COLOSSUS: You will
recover, Wade.
But then there was a third gentleman
You always do.
-who does the voice.
-REYNOLDS: Who does the voice. Yeah.
You ever see 127 Hours? Spoiler alert.
You ever see 127 Hours?
Spoiler alert.
REYNOLDS: That was
one of my favorite jokes,
which was the McAvoy or Stewart joke,
(SQUISHING NOISE)
which really kind of sums up Deadpool
Oh, my God.
in a very easy-to-digest way.
Just the understanding
of knowing he's in a movie,
Nasty.
the pop culture references
and the timelines.
WADE: Oh, there's
the money shot, baby.
(RETCHING)
Are You There God?
It's Me, Margaret.
WERNICK Yeah.
REESE: When it came time
to create Colossus' face,
there was an internal push to have his face
be captured by Rob Gronkowski,
(TRUCK HORN HONKS)
-to have them use Rob Gronkowski's face...
-REYNOLDS: Yes.
-...as the face for Colossus.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
WADE: Rock, meet bottom.
REESE: It didn't work out,
but it made us laugh.
And when life ends up
breathtakingly fucked...
WERNICK: The movie is told
in a non-linear format.
you can generally trace it
back to one big, bad decision.
It bounces in and out of time and space.
The one that sent you
down the road to Shitsburgh.
We did that for a number
of different reasons, one of which, uh...
This? Well, this was mine.
The big action sequence
which is on the freeway,
AGENT SMITH: Mr. Wilson.
extends over the course of
the almost first half of the movie.
Nothing warms my heart more than
a change of someone else's.
You finally hit "fuck it."
And we did that because budget was such
Just promise
you'll do right by me.
that we wanted to start the movie
with an action sequence
So I can do right
by someone else.
and have action sprinkled
throughout the first act,
Of course.
And please don't make
the super-suit green.
but couldn't afford to do
three different action sequences,
Or animated.
so we structured the film such that
(MAN CHOKING)
we started and then
bounced in and out of time and space.
MAN: Move it! Keep moving.
(PATIENT SCREAMING)
This place seems sanitary.
REESE: This was shot in an old World War I
munitions factory.
My first request
is warmer hands.
Oh! And, Jesus,
a warmer table.
So I think we all contracted
-some horrifying diseases by being there.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
It's gone now.
We should really come up
with a safe word, fellas.
This was the last thing that was ever...
I'm thinking
"pork and beans."
That building was ever used for.
It was bulldozed shortly after filming.
(GROANS) Easy.
Easy.
REYNOLDS". Probably
turned into condos, no doubt.
Aren't you a little strong for a lady?
Aren't you a little
strong for a lady?
I'm calling wang.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
REYNOLDS". Gina, so fun, so tough.
What's up with the matches?
But so gentle, for a fighter. She's a fighter
Oral fixation
or just a big Stallone fan?
(MUFFLED GROAN)
and she never felt that comfortable
manhandling me.
Patience, Angel.
I had to keep asking her to be rougher.
All in good time.
Are you here for
the turndown service, or what?
We have another talker.
REESE: And, Ed, who was just
an absolute true warrior.
I'm just excited about my
first day at superhero camp.
Shut the fuck up.
The most enthusiastic person
I think I've ever met.
-I've said that if he were. ..
-REYNOLDS: Oh...
...on the deck of the Thank:
and it were sinking,
Mr. Wilson, my name's Ajax.
he would be the only one
standing there doing a jig.
I manage this workshop.
He just doesn't have
a negative bone in his body.
REYNOLDS". Unflappable.
Ah, my welcome speech used to
be full of euphemisms like...
So, he's kind of
the perfect co-star, you know?
"This may hurt a little."
"This may cause you
some discomfort."
Just shows up ready to work every day.
But I've grown blunt.
-Good attitude. Yeah.
-WERNICK: Happy to be there.
This workshop is not
a government-led program.
It's a private institution that turns
reclamation projects like yourself...
REYNOLDS". And great. Just really filled
Ajax out exactly how we'd hoped.
into men of
extraordinary abilities.
But if you think superhuman powers
are acquired painlessly...
But if you think super-human
powers are acquired painlessly...
WERNICK: He wasn't written British,
Wrong.
(GROANS)
I'm injecting you
with a serum...
but when we found Ed, when Tim cast Ed,
that activates any mutant
genes lurking in your DNA.
For it to work we need to
subject you to extreme stress.
we thought, "You know what?
It really adds to the character
"to keep his British accent."
He's obviously British, so.
(WADE GROANING)
You've heard that whole "make an omelet,
break some eggs" bit, right?
I'm about to hurt you, Wade.
I was a patient here once myself, you know.
I was a patient here once
myself, you know.
The treatment affects everyone differently.
The treatment affects
everyone differently.
It made Angel inhumanly strong.
It made Angel
inhumanly strong.
REESE: When you're acting in pain,
do you rely on sense memory?
In my case,
it enhanced my reflexes.
Or how do you trick yourself
Also scorched my nerve endings,
so I no longer feel pain.
-into feeling pain that's not there?
{REYNOLDS CHUCKLES)
That's a good question.
I've certainly had enough
accidents in my life
And, in fact,
I no longer feel anything.
to know what it feels like
to kind of seize up like that,
(MUMBLING)
but, yeah, mostly you're just rigid
when you're in pain
and that's kind of what you're...
I don't know.
Thanks! Thank you. Thank you.
-I'm not really an actor, to be honest.
-(REESE AND WERNICK LAUGHING)
You have something
in your teeth.
Right in the middle there.
Just, I don't...
REYNOLDS". I actually have
a man's hand up my ass
A little nugget of romaine
lettuce or something.
-who's puppeting my body...
-(REESE LAUGHING)
(SIGHS)
...throughout the course of this.
It's been bothering me
for a long time.
It's my agent, actually.
REESE: Well, I would imagine acting,
in a lot of ways,
(LAUGHS)
Ah, made you look.
is an exercise in deluding yourself, right?
Hey, is Ajax
your actual name?
Because you're ultimately
deluding an audience,
Because it sounds
suspiciously made up.
but at some level you have
to delude yourself to feel the things
What is it, really?
Kevin? Bruce? Scott?
-that you're supposed to be feeling.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah, you just believe it.
Mitch? The Rickster?
And it sounds easy enough,
but it's not that easy.
(in British accent)
Is it Basil Fawlty?
Oh, joke away.
But you just believe it.
One thing that never
survives this place
You just make yourself believe.
is a sense of humor.
We'll see about that.
I suppose we will.
He's all yours.
Oh, come on.
You're gonna leave me all alone here
with less-angry Rosie O'Donnell?
You're gonna leave me
all alone here.
With less-angry
Rosie O'Donnell?
WERNICK: There's a string of about
15 or 20 Ryan ad-libs there of...
(GROANS)
REYNOLDS: Different...
FRANCIS: This is how
it's going to work.
Well, really, God bless Gina Carano
for being such a sport.
Adrenaline acts as a catalyst
for the serum...
I must have insulted her
so we're going
to have to make you suffer.
with every insult you could possibly...
FRANCIS: If you're lucky,
the mutant genes will activate
WERNICK: Jose Canseco.
REESE: China. Kevin Sorbo.
and manifest in
a spectacular fashion.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, the, um...
-Cries Angel Mindfreak.
-WERNICK: Cries Angel Mindfreak.
(GASPS)
REESE: The Busta Rhymes.
REYNOLDS: Busta Rhymes. (LAUGHS)
FRANCIS: If not, well, we'll
have to keep on hurting you...
WERNICK: I don't know,
are those going to be on the DVD?
(WADE SHIVERING)
-I hope so.
-REYNOLDS: I hope so, too-
in new and different ways,
REYNOLDS: I'm trying to remember,
there were a few more in there.
each more painful
than the last...
until you finally mutate.
REESE: And that ice bath was what,
warm water with plastic cubes in it?
REYNOLDS". That ice bath
was boiling hot actually.
Or die.
It was too hot for me to stay in.
And then to pretend
like you're freezing was just...
WERNICK: And the goo was freezing,
was it the goo?
REYNOLDS". No, the goo was just
the slipperiest substance known to man.
CUNNINGHAM:
You mean a bucket list?
WADE: Like a fuck-it list.
I couldn't actually walk out of there
back to the trailer to get cleaned up.
I'd really like
to light a spliff
off the Olympic torch.
And it doesn't come off.
CUNNINGHAM: Pass it
to me right after.
It took me two days to get it off.
WERNICK: And the tub was
too small too, right?
Let's not forget naked
tandem base-jumping
REYNOLDS". Oh, yeah,
it was just a fucking nightmare.
with the WNBA's
Sacramento Monarchs.
Anything on my bucket list
would involve public nudity.
Finally, giving Meredith
Baxter-Birney a Dutch oven.
WERNICK: That's Worm,
Worm is from the comics.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, he's in the comics.
No. Receiving a Dutch oven
from Meredith Baxter-Birney.
REESE: I don't think he's ever called Worm
in the movie, is he?
(LAUGHS)
REYNOLDS: Nope.
WERNER. It's Cunningham.
REESE: Cunningham.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, we call him Cunningham.
Making banana pancakes
for my kids.
WERNICK: Which, I think, is his actual name.
REYNOLDS". Yeah, of course.
WERNICK: And then his nickname is Worm.
Vanessa.
I wanna see Vanessa.
WADE: I wanna see Vanessa.
FRANCIS: You're lovely.
REESE: I want my whole life to be lit
like that Vanessa moment right there.
I don't know about
anyone else, but I'm touched.
REYNOLDS: Right? God, I know.
REESE: Just to be walking through
a Liz Taylor commercial.
We were just joking.
No, no. It's okay.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, just... Oh...
REESE: White diamonds.
REYNOLDS: Right.
I encourage distractions.
I'm wearing white diamonds right now.
Wouldn't want you giving up
on us, now would we?
Hey, don't take any shit from him,
Cunningham.
Hey, don't take any shit
from him, Cunningham.
REESE: I love this look
when he hears the word, "Francis."
How tough can he be...
with a name like Francis?
I love seeing those eyes go up.
Ed's face has...
Francis?
REYNOLDS". It's like a snake.
WADE: That's his legal name.
REESE: Yeah, it's like
it casts shadows almost. It's so cool.
(CHUCKLING) He got "Ajax"
from the dish soap.
WERNER Ajax from a dish soap.
F, R, A, N, C, I...
Huge laugh.
Probably, in audiences we've seen,
Oops!
probably the third biggest laugh
of the movie.
REYNOLDS". Yeah.
REESE". And we didn't see it coming at all.
Snagged the dry cleaning tag
off your lab coat.
REYNOLDS: No, I never thought
it was really...
WERNICK: In fact, Ajax, I don't even think
is a dish soap, is it?
FYI, I could probably get you
the superhero discount.
REYNOLDS: It is a cleaning product.
You are so
relentlessly annoying.
Thanks.
-An abrasive cleaning product.
REESE". A cleanser, yeah.
Never heard that before.
REYNOLDS: I think it's like an all-purpose
counter cleaner or something.
Why don't you do us all
a favor and shut the fuck up?
We just gave them about 500 grand
worth of advertising, by the way.
Or I'll sew
your pretty mouth shut.
(REESE LAUGHING)
Oh...
I wouldn't do that
if I were you.
REYNOLDS: Right there.
See, here's the problem
with round-the-clock torture...
See, here's the problem with
round-the-clock torture...
is that you can't really
step it up from there.
REYNOLDS". To the three people that listen
to a DVD commentary.
REESE: Yes.
WERNICK: Which will be us three
Is that what you think?
-and that's it.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
REESE: We have dirty kitchens.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, absolutely.
REESE: We may need...
FRANCIS: If this doesn't
unlock your mutation, then, well...
If this doesn't unlock
your mutation, then, well...
REYNOLDS: This fucking machine.
I felt like I lived in it for two weeks
nothing will.
even though it wasn't that long, but...
Now, what we're going to do is
lower the oxygen
concentration in the air...
God.
to the exact point you feel
like you're suffocating.
WERNICK: In the script,
it was called the Punch Bowl.
I don't think
it's called the Punch Bowl anymore.
If your brainwaves slow,
REYNOLDS". It's not anymore, yeah.
WERNICK: It's not anymore.
meaning you're
about to pass out...
REYNOLDS: But it really was... I really
was completely strapped into it.
then we'll turn up the O2.
If your heart rate slows...
And it was just a...
Always a slightly disconcerting feeling
meaning you're able
to catch your breath...
we'll turn it back down.
to know that if that building caught on fire,
I'd basically be fucked.
And that's where
we'll leave you.
Right there.
-People would be using me as a door mat.
REESE: We were all gonna run.
Oh, and I thought
you guys were dicks before.
-REYNOLDS: Climbing over me...
-(REESE LAUGHING)
FRANCIS: You know
the funniest part of this?
...just to scramble outside.
REESE". Come on, now, we would have...
You still think we're making
you a superhero.
REYNOLDS: Wheeled me out?
REESE: Like the old pharaohs.
You. A dishonorable discharge.
We would have climbed
in there with you
-and gotten burned alive.
-(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
Hip-deep in hookers.
REESE". Just to honor your sacrifice.
You're nothing.
WERNICK: I think the original Punch Bowl,
Little secret, Wade.
the first Punch Bowl that came out was...
This workshop
doesn't make superheroes,
I think cost three quarters
of a million dollars,
we make super-slaves.
I think, to make that prop.
I think it was our most expensive prop,
We're gonna fit you
with a control collar
next to your suit, which was
a little bit more expensive.
and auction you off
to the highest bidder.
REYNOLDS: That Punch Bowl
cost three quarters of a million dollars?
Who knows what
they'll have you doing?
WERNICK: Yes.
REYNOLDS: No.
Terrorizing citizens,
putting down freedom fighters.
WERNICK: Yes, the first one did.
REYNOLDS: Not this one, though.
WERNICK: Yes.
REYNOLDS: Wait, really?
WERNICK Yeah.
REYNOLDS". I should know that.
That's... What?
Maybe just mow
the occasional lawn.
WERNICK: I'm pretty sure that's the case.
REESE: Maybe you just made that up.
REYNOLDS: I don't believe you.
What the fuck
is wrong with you?
-There's no way.
REESE". We're getting to the bottom of this.
WERNICK: Stand by.
REESE: Yeah, someone's in trouble.
FRANCIS: You're never
going home after this.
You're never going home
after this.
Now there's a brave face.
WERNICK". And, my God,
when Ryan acted this scene.
Wait, wait! Wait. Wait.
The breaths and the fighting for... It's...
Seriously, you actually have
something in your teeth now.
REESE: Well, you could watch
everyone at the monitors just...
WERNER I Still... It's Still...
REESE: They were so ill at ease
Enjoy your weekend.
just because it made them feel
like they were gasping for breath.
"Weekend"? Back up.
Weekend?
It was tough to watch.
(MACHINE HISSING)
REYNOLDS". Suffocating.
What a terrible way to go.
WERNICK: It's brilliantly acted.
Oh, my God.
And this must've been one of the harder
scenes just physically for you to do, Ryan,
(GASPING)
(CHOKING)
in terms of just what it took your body...
The toll it took on your body,
this was intense.
REYNOLDS". There was a lot of stuff
we cut out,
which is really the hardest part of it, I think.
(EKG BEEPING)
But we kept a few pieces in
and it was worth it.
(CHOKING)
(EKG BEEPING RAPIDLY)
WERNICK: Oh...
REESE: Yeah, I think we ended up trimming
down what was originally there
because it was so oppressive.
-It was just...
-REYNOLDS: It was a little intense.
WERNICK: How did that
feel on your skin, Ryan?
REYNOLDS; (CHUCKLES)
What?
REESE: This is VFX.
REYNOLDS: Computer-generated...
WERNICK: (CHUCKLES) I know.
REYNOLDS". Good Lord.
WADE: Did I say this was a love story?
WADE: Did I say
this was a love story?
No, it's a horror movie.
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
REYNOLDS: There he is.
FRANCIS: Fucking hell.
Looks like someone lost his shot
at Homecoming King.
Looks like someone lost his
shot at Homecoming King.
What have you done to me?
I've merely raised your stress levels
high enough to trigger a mutation.
I've merely raised
your stress levels
high enough
to trigger a mutation.
You sadistic fuck!
I've cured you, Wade.
REYNOLDS: Now, some comic book fans
will be sad to hear
Now your mutated cells
can heal anything.
that there was a scene that we cut out
It's attacking your cancer
as fast as it can form.
which actually has, Killebrew,
Dr. Killebrew in this sequence
Yeah, I've seen similar
side-effects before.
that, after unbelievable debate,
we took out of the film.
I could cure them...
but where's the fun in that?
But it was with a heavy heart
we took it out.
But it just had to go, it was...
Now, I'm gonna
shut you in again, Wade.
WERNER It was just one more layer
in the bad guy plot.
REYNOLDS: Slowing us down.
Not because I need to.
WERNER That Ajax really worked
for Dr. Killebrew,
who you didn't know was the mastermind
until the very end of the movie.
Because I want to.
REESE". Mmm-hmm.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I think audiences
just got a little bit confused
about the hierarchy and it just made sense,
ultimately, to simplify it.
REYNOLDS". Yeah, and it's just
a straight revenge story
you don't really want to mess with,
Oh, well.
and it's between these two guys.
Go ahead.
It's between Wade Wilson and Ajax.
Oh, you smell like shit.
And adding that extra layer was tough,
it was tough to digest.
(GRUNTS)
Whoa! (LAUGHS)
ANGEL DUST: Motherfucker.
WERNICK: Talk about the makeup, Ryan,
Hey, hey, hey.
It's all right, it's all right.
-how long of a process was it...
-REYNOLDS: (CLICKS TONGUE) Oh...
I think we owe him
that one, yeah?
...to put you in the face
and at times the full body makeup?
You take off. Go on.
Off you go.
Well, the full body one, it's just a pain
in the ass that's unavoidable.
But this one's not too bad,
when you do arms and face.
It's about, uh, five hours.
That's about five hours.
But when you do full body
Quick question.
which is the sequence that comes up after
this, so head-to-toe naked fight scene,
What's my name?
full body, that's about eight or nine hours.
-And then you do a 15-hour shoot day...
-WERNICK: Oh, boy.
...and you're working 25, 26 hours in a day,
Didn't think so.
so tough days, but you don't complain.
WADE: Sorry, Francis.
My lips are sealed.
You just remind yourself
that you're getting to make Deadpool
after 10 years of waiting.
(GROANING)
WERNICK: So, hours to put it on,
and what about 30 seconds
-to just rip it off yourself, right?
-(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
At the end of each day, man,
I was counting the seconds to rip it off
and I would do it with my hands,
which would totally aggravate our sweet,
incredible, genius makeup artist Bill Corso
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
because he was worried about my skin,
'cause when you rip it off it's epoxied
to your skin, so it's kind of damaging,
but I didn't care,
I was just dying to get home.
WERNER And you spend about a third,
a third, a third, I think.
We broke it down.
A third in the costume.
A third in the makeup.
A third as unscarred Wade Wilson,
before he became Deadpool.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, that was...
Well, the sort of equation
we felt would work best for the studio.
(EXPLODING)
And it ended up
working best for the film, too...
-WERNICK: Yup.
-...which aren't always the same, so...
REESE: I like the fact that, uh...
That you got out by virtue of this match.
I think a lot of times, as a screenwriter,
(MEN SCREAMING
IN THE DISTANCE)
you're trying to get your protagonist
locked in a box.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(MAN COUGHING)
And then figure out how to get them out
in a way that's not overly obvious.
And we planted that match
in the mouth of Angel Dust,
always with the intent
to have it be the device
that Wade used to get out
of the Punch Bowl. That's kind of cool.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, I always loved that, too.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
That was a nice plant pay-off,
as you call it.
These scenes were fun.
(GROANS)
Ed Skrein is so physically gifted
and he spent months and months
training with fighters and all kinds of stuff,
(GRUNTING)
and I think it really shows in this sequence.
He's so good, physically.
Just has this kind of simian quality,
which is great.
(GROANING)
You don't want to kill me.
I'm the only one
who can fix your ugly mug.
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHS)
WERNICK". Your penis there,
(GROANING)
that's your actual penis, yes, Ryan?
-(REESE LAUGHING)
-REYNOLDS: Of course it is.
(REYNOLDS CHUCKLES)
100%.
My penis looks like pepperoni flatbread.
(WERNICK AND REESE LAUGHING)
WERNICK: I can vouch for that.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
(GRUNTS LOUDLY)
(RETCHING)
(GRUNTS AND LAUGHS)
REYNOLDS: Kind of a terrible way to die,
I would imagine.
(GRUNTING)
WERNICK". But a great way
to discover your powers.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
(WADE BREATHING HEAVILY)
What's my name?
REYNOLDS". That fucking room.
Had to be 145 degrees.
I mean, it was just intense.
CUNNINGHAM: Wade.
So much fire,
so much heat trapped in there.
Fire marshal kept shutting us down
because the interior temperature
rose to such a degree
that it was a huge fire hazard, so...
It was a long, slow day.
WERNICK: And this was
the 25-hour day, right?
REYNOLDS". This was the 25-hour
shooting day for me.
REESE: It's not as though we were shooting
in an ex-munitions factory
that might explode.
REYNOLDS: (LAUGHS) I know.
Ugh, genius location manager.
REYNOLDS". Another sort of God-awful...
REESE: Yeah, this scene
was originally followed by a sequence
in which Wade tested out
his invulnerability
by committing suicide in ridiculous ways.
And it... Gosh, it made us laugh.
He was throwing himself
out of subway cars,
and jumping into polar bear enclosures,
and doing all kinds of...
All kinds of self-destructive things.
But ultimately I think that, for the tone,
it just made more sense
to keep this reasonably serious.
WERNICK: The tone of this movie, it was
a real, you know, juggling act
(GROANS)
in terms of bouncing in and out
of darkness and humor and...
WADE: I didn't just get
the cure to el cancer...
If done wrong, it can be a disaster.
I got the cure
to el everything.
It can feel, you know,
schizophrenic and inconsistent,
But there was
only one thing...
but I think, you know,
we all managed to string together
that really mattered.
the movie in such a way
that the tone really does work.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
It's a ride, you know, in and out...
REYNOLDS: Mmm-hmm.
...of fun and tragedy, and sadness and...
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
REYNOLDS". Made the edit room
a real roller coaster ride, though.
-There was a lot of different...
-WERNICK: Yes.
REYNOLDS: When you shoot a movie
that has a fractured narrative like this,
you can really kind of...
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
You can compose the movie
in so many different ways,
and so many different timelines.
(INFANT CRYING)
I mean, at one point,
we experimented with a linear timeline
which was just a disaster,
a nightmare for us, 'cause it was never...
WOMAN: Come on, let's go.
Obviously, it was never written that way
by Rhett and Paul and it just...
Presented a lot of problems but, um...
WOMAN: Oh, that must hurt.
WERNER And again, I think
that has to do with tone, it's, you know...
Thank you so much.
The origin story of Deadpool is so dark.
(INDISTINCT
CONVERSATIONS CONTINUE)
You know, a character who has cancer
who loses his, you know...
You know,
scarring and loses his girl.
God, he's so fucking gnarly.
I feel like the non-linear nature allowed us
to bounce in and out
WOMAN: Look at his face.
MAN: Oh, my God. Poor guy.
of, you know, tones that created
not too much darkness
FEMALE PEDESTRIAN:
Honey, don't stare.
MALE PEDESTRIAN: Freak.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
over a long period of time,
that you could give the audience
breaks of the darkness,
amongst the comedy and lightness...
-REYNOLDS: Hmm.
-...of him being Deadpool.
REYNOLDS". Typical summer day
in Vancouver, British Columbia.
No way. I'm not making
her life as ugly as mine.
Come on, Wade, it can't be that bad.
Come on, Wade,
it can't be that bad.
Bullshit!
Ah, bullshit!
I'm a monster inside and out.
I belong in a fucking circus.
Wade, Vanessa loves you.
She doesn't care what you...
Oh! Oh.
Do you like what you see?
REYNOLDS: You could've cut together
an entire film
No.
You look like an avocado
just of T. J. Miller doing
alternate jokes here.
had sex with an older,
more disgusting avocado.
Not gently. Like it was hate-fucking.
Yeah.
Not gently.
Like it was hate-fucking.
There was something wrong
with the relationship...
(WERNICK CHUCKLES)
...and that was the only catharsis that
they could find...
and that was
the only catharsis
REYNOLDS". The only reason we stopped
shooting the scene
that they could find
without violence.
was 'cause T.J., eventually,
had to go to sleep.
And the only guy
who can fix this fugly mug...
(REESE LAUGHING)
is the British shitstick
who ran the mutant factory.
-We also shot the scene twice.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah. This is the second...
And he's gone. Poof!
REESE: Because we had to alter some key
information in the middle of it,
Yeah, well you gotta do
something to remedy this...
so we shot this whole scene,
and it was working great,
because as of now,
you only have
one course of action.
and then we had to go back and do it again.
Damn straight.
And we were afraid,
"Are we gonna recapture the magic?"
Find Francis.
Star in horror films.
But thanks to Ryan and T.J.'s comic
chemistry, it worked out.
What?
Star in your own horror films.
Because you look
like Freddy Krueger
REYNOLDS: Yeah, this is a full six months
after shooting finished.
face-fucked
a topographical map of Utah.
Here's what
I'm actually gonna do.
I'm gonna work through his crew
until somebody gives up Francis...
I'm gonna work
through his crew
until somebody
gives up Francis...
force him to fix this,
then put a bullet in his skull...
force him to fix this, then
put a bullet in his skull...
and fuck the brain hole.
I don't wanna see that
or think of it again.
REYNOLDS". That is kind of stolen
from Dan Aykroyd in Grosse Pointe Blank
when he says
But the douchebag does
thinks you're dead, right?
that he's gonna fuck
the brain-hole of someone,
Yeah.
That's good.
You should keep it that way.
and I always loved that.
What, like, wear a mask?
Yes. A very thick mask.
All the time.
WERNICK: A big reference point for you.
Grosse Pointe Blank, you love that movie.
I am sorry...
REYNOLDS: I do love Grosse Pointe Blank,
I'm a little obsessed with it.
you are haunting.
WERNICK: Great movie.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Your face is
the stuff of nightmares.
Like a testicle with teeth.
You will die alone.
I mean, if you could die.
Ideally, for others' sake.
(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
That'll do.
All you need now is a suit
and a nickname...
like Wade the Wisecracker...
REYNOLDS: I don't know why "dying alone"
or Scaredevil,
Mr. Neverdie.
makes me laugh more
than any other joke in that.
Oh, shit.
What?
I put all my money on you and now...
I put all my money
on you and now...
I just realized I'm never gonna win the, uh...
I just realized
I'm never gonna win the, uh...
Dead pool.
Captain Deadpool.
Captain Deadpool...
No, just...
-Just Deadpool, yeah.
-Just Deadpool.
Just Deadpool, yeah.
Just Deadpool.
To you, Mr. Pool.
Deadpool.
That sounds like a fucking franchise.
That sounds like
a fucking franchise.
REYNOLDS". Oh, I was always
so uncomfortable with that line!
(GLASSES CLINK)
WERNICK: Audiences love it.
REESE: It gets a laugh, though.
REYNOLDS: Yup.
REESE: It gets a laugh.
REESE: Yeah, originally
this montage was, um,
believe it or not,
just Deadpool going on random kills
This shit's gonna
have nuts in it.
while Ajax was waiting to get out of prison.
(MAN GROANS)
Where's Francis?
Ajax had gone to prison
at the end of the workshop fight.
(GRUNTING)
And Deadpool was just biding his time,
waiting for Ajax to get out of prison.
(GUN FIRING)
(GROANING)
But somebody, I think it might
have been Simon, had the bright idea
to make this montage
into a search for Ajax.
(SIGHS)
WADE: Where's Francis?
So, Ajax doesn't go to prison,
and Deadpool goes on a
month-to-year-long search
for his arch enemy.
REYNOLDS". Which is why
we had to fucking change
AL: Seltzer water
and lemon for blood.
that whole bar scene, too, which was...
REESE: Yeah, and it gave it
some propulsive energy.
Or wear red. Dumbass.
I mean, you're starting to feel
like Deadpool's got a goal here,
-and obviously it's to find Francis.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
WERNICK: And it's worth mentioning,
you know,
(ALL CHEERING)
Simon was really our guardian angel
on this movie,
-you know, he...
-REYNOLDS: Very true.
WERNICK: He came aboard, uh...
(CLAMORING)
Fox has immense trust in him.
He's the keeper of the X-Universe and, uh...
(GROANING)
(GUN FIRING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
WADE: Don't make me
ask twice.
And he came aboard
and we were off to the races, and...
Where...
is Francis?
REYNOLDS: Mainly, he just really protected
the tone and the vibe of Deadpool, and...
He made me ask twice.
Is the mask muffling my voice?
WERNICK: Yes.
REYNOLDS: He was a huge asset to us.
He's amazing.
Where's Francis?
(GUN FIRING)
Where the fuck is Francis?
(GROANING)
WERNICK: I'm on that board somewhere,
a picture of me.
(GROANING)
(WADE LAUGHING)
I don't think it's in the movie.
You're about to be killed
by a Zamboni.
(REYNOLDS CHUCKLES)
WADE: Where's Francis?
Where's Francis?
REYNOLDS". The Zamboni idea
was our first AD.
(WOMAN WHIMPERS)
No! Please!
Oh, God! I'm so sorry!
That was his idea,
to shoot a kill with the Zamboni,
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
-and I love it.
-WERNICK: Yeah.
Oh! You little
spider monkey!
REYNOLDS". Good Canadian joke right there.
(TOILET FLUSHING)
Where... is... Francis?
This is confusing.
Is it sexist to hit you?
Is it more sexist to not hit you?
Is it more sexist
to not hit you?
I mean, the line gets real... blurry.
I mean, the line
gets real... blurry.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
WHERE IS FRANCIS?
WERNICK: In case you were wondering
what "Dénde esté Francesca" means...
Tell me where
your fucking boss is
REYNOLDS". Jesus.
WERNER "Where is Francis?"
REYNOLDS: That drives Paul insane.
or you're gonna die!
WERNICK: Insane, I'm sorry.
In five minutes!
REYNOLDS: And I'm With him On that one.
I have no idea why we subtitled that.
WERNICK Agent Smith.
555-0199.
Ryan Reynolds' number.
(WHISPERS)
Don't hesitate to call me.
REYNOLDS: (WHISPERS)
Call me.
-(WHISPERS) Call me.
-(WERNICK CHUCKLES)
WERNICK: Those are bags of rice.
REYNOLDS: Those are... Yeah.
-(GRUFFLY) "Rice to see you!"
-WERNICK: "Why?"
-REYNOLDS: That was a joke we wanted...
-(WERNICK LAUGHS)
Nice to see you, Jared.
(LAUGHS) ...to get in there but we didn't.
WADE: I'll take the foot long...
I'll take the footlong...
REYNOLDS". Fully loaded.
Fully loaded.
WERNICK: A little known fact,
(GRUNTING)
(GUNS FIRING)
we spend most of our days
around the house
quoting the movie ourselves.
(PANTING)
(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
REYNOLDS: That's true.
(GRUNTS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
REESE: I love that violent hit right there.
WERNICK: That's great and violent.
(GROANS) Whoa, whoa!
We did that about
six or seven times to make that work.
41 confirmed kills.
Now it's 89.
About to be 90.
REYNOLDS: God, that was
a nasty hit, though.
It was practical. It was real.
Mr. Wilson?
Ding-ding.
You're looking very alive.
You're looking
very alive.
Ha! Only on the outside.
Ha! Only on the outside!
-This is not going to end well for me, is it?
-This is not gonna end well for you, no.
This is not going to
end well for me, is it?
This is not gonna
end well for you, no.
Where's your boss?
I can tell you exactly...
(SHUSHING MOCKINGLY)
Oh, you'll tell me, but first...
Oh, you'll tell me.
But first...
You might wanna look away for this.
You might wanna
look away for this.
Now this little piggy went to...
Now this little piggy
went to...
(AGENT SMITH SCREAMS)
WADE: Thank you, Agent Smith.
Taxi!
Hop in! Great day for a ride.
(HINDI SONG PLAYING ON RADIO)
WADE: And we all know
how this turned out.
REESE: Uh-oh, here it comes.
-There it is.
-(REYNOLDS CHUCKLES)
Whoops!
You weren't meant to see that.
REYNOLDS: I have that unicorn upstairs.
REESE: That's...
WERNER The, uh, third film
you've masturbated in, Ryan?
REYNOLDS". It is the third feature length film
that I have masturbated in.
There. All caught up.
WERNICK: And what are the other two?
REYNOLDS: The Nines
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
and The Change Up
are the two other films
that I have made love to myself in.
We're here.
I'm not proud to say.
WERNICK: That is an impressive
filmography of masturbation.
(GROANS) Sorry about
bleeding in all your garbage.
REYNOLDS: Thank you.
Thank you very much.
People have gotten a star on the Walk
of Fame in Hollywood for less, my friend.
(GRUNTS)
(WERNICK AND REESE LAUGHING)
Seltzer water and
lemon for blood.
Whoo!
Some kinds of anger can't be managed...
Some kinds of anger
can't be managed...
RE ESE: Always looks like, it always looks
like that rag already has blood all over it.
like the kind where
your year-long plan
ends with the wrong guy
getting dismembered!
REYNOLDS". I know.
It does, doesn't it?
Didn't even think about it
when we were shooting.
That said, when it comes time
to licking wounds,
there's no place like home.
REESE: Just gonna pick up
my bloody rag and...
REYNOLDS: Yeah, the one
I usually grab when...
Ah, and I share that home
with someone you've met,
REESE; Yes.
the old blind lady
from the laundromat, Al.
REYNOLDS: Lost an appendage.
God, I miss cocaine.
(REYNOLDS GROANS)
WERNICK: In the script, Blind Al was
introduced a little bit earlier than this.
Her.
(GASPS) Fourth-wall break
inside a fourth-wall break.
In the fractured narrative.
That's like 16 walls.
She's like Robin to my Batman,
REYNOLDS". She was so much fun.
except she's old,
and black, and blind.
Leslie Uggams is just such a trooper,
she'll just...
And I think
she's in love with me.
And this doesn't make her a trooper,
but it makes me adore her.
WADE: Wait, pretty sure
Robin loves Batman, too.
Which is, she'll just kind of...
ls just game for anything.
We just threw her that line like,
"God, I miss cocaine- "
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
And she just says it
without even thinking about it. (LAUGHS)
WERNICK: Oh, she's great.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
REYNOLDS: She is just so...
WERNICK: And a very talented actress.
(AL GROANS)
REYNOLDS". And an incredible singer,
one of the great singers.
WADE: Al?
Morning, sleepyhead.
WERNICK: Was in Roots, yes?
(GRUNTS)
It smells like
old lady pants in here.
I'm not gonna go there
'cause I'm not 100% sure
Yes, I'm old.
I wear pants.
but I know she sang with Frank Sinatra.
She's done a...
But you're no lady.
Oh! So comfy.
REESE: She was on The Muppet Show,
I know that.
REYNOLDS: Oh, yeah.
Upside of being blind:
I've never seen you in Crocs.
WERNICK: Uh, talk about the Croce, Ryan.
That was a Ryan, um...
You mean my big,
rubber masturbating shoes?
REYNOLDS". Oh, yeah, the big, rubber,
masturbating shoes.
AL: Yes, I know.
Downside of being blind...
Yeah, the Croce were sort of an addition
that we liked, I don't know, just to
I hear everything
in this duplex.
-you know, adding as much...
-WERNICK: Character, yeah.
(GROANS)
...kind of weird character
with Deadpool as possible.
Sit on a stick.
Bactin?
I like that he had his specific shoes
that he liked to masturbate with.
Yeah. Bactin should do it.
How's that Kullen
coming along?
The Ikea is something that the boys here
IKEA doesn't assemble itself,
you know.
had in the script for six years which is...
I love.
You're telling me.
I don't mind the Kullen.
It's an improvement
on the Hurdal.
WERNICK: Just weird, you know, it's...
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Please. Anything's an
improvement over the Hurdal.
WERNER But it's Deadpool weird
and that's why it works.
I'd have taken an Hemnes
or a Trysil over the Hurdal.
REESE: I just like that they have
this whole language, this whole
Oh, no, I didn't get excited
till I saw the Kullen.
-(CHUCKLES) Swedish language, there.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Screw, please.
REYNOLDS: This was actually our first
official day of shooting, though.
Here? Now?
Just kidding.
I know it's been decades.
You'd be surprised.
WERNICK: And you know, it's interesting
Pretty grossed out.
because the, you know, the
traditional studio note would be,
(GROANS) Ta... Da.
"Wait, he just lost his arm, his girl
and the bad guy,
"and he's talking about Ikea?"
I wish I never heard
of Craigslist.
"That doesn't work.
You've got to get him back on track."
And I quote,
"Looking for roommate,
"blind to
life's imperfections.
"Must be good with hands."
You know, again,
Deadpool allows you to break all the rules
Or would you rather I build
the IKEA, and you pay rent?
and we jumped at the chance.
Why such a douche
this morning?
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Let's recap.
The cock thistle that
turned me into this freak...
REESE: I think the only rule with Deadpool
is to break the rules.
slipped through
my arms today...
REYNOLDS". True.
REESE". If that makes sense.
Arm.
Catching him was my only chance to be
hot again, get my super sexy ex back...
Catching him was
my only chance
to be hot again,
get my super sexy ex back...
REYNOLDS: And then,
we 're back on point here,
and prevent this shit from
happening to someone else.
we're sort of saying what's really going on.
So, yeah,
today was about as much fun
WERNICK: That is lavender wasabi lotion?
as a sandpaper dildo.
REYNOLDS: Lavender wasabi lotion,
my unicorn wearing ass less leather chaps,
(WADE FARTS)
# driveby.
and the unicorn has a tiny penis.
For the record.
WERNER Nevin Swain.
REYNOLDS". Nevin Swain,
our incredible props guy.
I would call Nevin in the middle
of the night and say,
"Nevin, I need a tiny, stuffed unicorn
wearing ass less chaps and...
"And a proportionate penis."
Found out who our friend
in the red suit is.
And he would have that for me
pretty much within 12 hours.
(REESE LAUGHING)
Fucking Wade Wilson.
WERNICK: And he would say, "Is this
for the movie or your personal needs?"
I suppose I'd wear a mask too
if I had a face like that.
REYNOLDS: And we would... Often times,
-the line was blurred.
-WERNICK: Both.
I only wish I healed the same.
(WERNICK LAUGHS)
REYNOLDS: I can't even get an erection
-unless I have a unicorn in the room.
-(WERNICK LAUGHS)
Still, we'll put him
out of our misery.
I just... I don't even care who knows that.
Obviously, 'cause I'm saying it
on the commentary.
On our terms.
Right.
And when he heals?
REESE: Oh, my...
He can't.
Not if there's nothing
left of him to heal.
You know, it's funny.
I almost miss the fucker.
I like a challenge.
But he's bad for business.
But he's bad
for business.
Now let's go find him.
Now let's go
find him.
Oh.
(WADE GRUNTS SLOWLY)
Tylenol PM?
REYNOLDS". What I love about
this scene is that
You can stick that
where you stuck the Bactin.
there's a weirdly, like, sweet energy
between Blind Al and Wade.
I raided my stash
of wisdom tooth Percocet...
and I am orbiting
fucking Saturn right now.
In a weird way, it kind of lets us forgive
(SIGHS)
how hostile they are toward each other
half the time, you know.
But I appreciate the gesture.
WERNICK: Yeah, I mean, you know, it's...
Am I crazy,
or is your hand really small?
You love this woman and she loves you.
And it's really, um...
As abusive as the relationship is, it's...
About the size of
a KFC spork.
Ugh.
There's a real love behind it and a warmth.
I get why you're so pissy...
but your mood's
never gonna brighten
Find this woman...
and tell her how you feel.
till you find this woman...
What do I keep telling you, Mrs. Magoo?
She wouldn't have me.
What do I keep telling you,
Mrs. Magoo?
She wouldn't have me.
WERNICK: She's like the oracle here,
you know.
If you could see me,
you'd understand.
Looks aren't everything.
Looks are everything.
You ever heard David Beckham speak?
You ever heard
David Beckham speak?
It's like he mouth-sexed
a can of helium.
REESE: Not many movies
where the protagonist is played by an actor
You think Ryan Reynolds
got this far
and references that same actor
within the movie.
on his superior acting method?
Love is blind, Wade.
No.
You're blind.
So, you're just gonna lie there
and whimper?
So, you're just gonna
lie there and whimper?
WERNICK: And in the comics,
Ryan Reynolds is referenced in the comics.
No, I'm gonna wait till this
arm plows through puberty...
REESE: He is, yeah.
and then I'm gonna
come up with
a whole new
Christmas Day plan.
In the meantime,
you might wanna leave the room.
you might wanna
leave the room.
I bet it feels huge in this hand.
I bet it feels huge
in this hand.
WERNICK: I say that line all the time.
Go, go, go.
(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
WEASEL: So, the doctor says,
"The bad news is
you don't have that long to live."
"you don't have
that long to live."
So, the patient says,
"How long do I have?"
The doctor says, "Five."
REESE: This was a joke that
T.J. just broke out on the day.
The guy says, "Five what?"
-And we thought it was nice...
-REYNOLDS: Is it?
And the doctor says,
"Four, three, two..."
REESE: 'Cause it dovetailed thematically.
REYNOLDS: Is it an original joke of his?
(ALL LAUGHING)
WERNER I don't think So.
REESE: No, I just think it's one
of those classic jokes
that you just hear
and it gets told and retold.
REYNOLDS: I can never tell a joke.
Like, I have never...
I can't retain them for some reason.
Can I help you ladies?
I've never been able
to be that guy who just...
WERNICK: No. My dad is a great,
great joke-teller. ..
Oh, I do hope so.
-REYNOLDS: Really?
-...one of the great joke-tellers, yeah.
-I don't have that...
-REYNOLDS: Such a gift.
I heard you might be
able to point me
WERNICK ll' is.
in the direction
of a, um, friend of mine.
REESE: Well, T.J.'s got a bunch of them.
Name of Wade Wilson.
He is a student of comedy.
REYNOLDS". He really is.
REESE". And the history of comedy,
Sorry.
I don't know the name.
and stand-up and joke-telling.
Just everything, he's the guy.
WERNICK". We called him
Benjamin Button on set
Hey, you're not supposed
to be behind the bar.
because he would always button a scene
with an improv joke.
REYNOLDS: (LAUGHS) Yeah.
WERNICK: He does it at the back end here.
I've seen this girl.
REYNOLDS". He does about 50 of them
at the back end here,
FRANCIS:
Ah, this must be Vanessa.
where we had to, eventually,
run out of digital...
I've heard so much about you.
(GROANING)
Sweetheart, you might wanna look around.
Um, sweetheart,
you might wanna look around.
This isn't really the place
to do something like that.
Easy, Angel.
Put the little man down.
We have everything we need now.
REESE: Yeah, I mean
there's some funny people
We have everything
we need now.
who turn it on for the camera
and aren't funny in real life.
You sure?
You don't want any clothes
that are not monochromatic?
And T.J.'s not one of those.
He's funny in real life, too.
Have fun at your midnight
showing of Blade II.
REYNOLDS: Very funny.
Whoo!
Whoo.
Thanks for having my back, guys.
Thanks for having
my back, guys.
Wade, we have a fucking problem.
And by "we," I mean "you."
Wade, we have
a fucking problem.
And by "we," I mean "you."
I can't believe I'm doing this.
Ah, I can't believe
I'm doing this.
ls there a word for half afraid,
half angry?
Is there a word for
half afraid, half angry?
Yeah, "afrangry," I guess.
Yeah, "afrangry",
I guess.
Have you decided what
you're gonna say to her?
Fuck me!
Maybe not start with that.
Uh, maybe not
start with that.
(TRAP MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, coming onto our stage...
Hey, coming onto
our stage right now...
WERNICK Stan Lee.
...give it up for Chastity!
give it up for Chastity!
REYNOLDS". Here's a great Stan Lee cameo.
(ALL CHEERING)
Or as I like to call her, Irony.
Or as I like
to call her, Irony.
REESE: There was a thought
that we needed to make
Better find her fast
before numbnuts does.
Stan Lee's dialogue as realistic as possible,
How do you know
she's in here?
Because I'm constantly
stalking that fox.
so Paul got assigned the task
of talking to the real strip club MC
and writing down lines
that he might really say
LAUGHS} and handing them to Stan Lee.
WERNER Really kind of the low point
of my screenwriting career...
RE ESE: That was probably the low point
of Paul's career.
...when I'm sitting across
from a guy...
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
...and he's saying,
"Show me them big ol'' titties!"
REYNOLDS: Oh, God.
Needless to say,
Stan didn't say any of those lines.
REESE: He was game to do it,
WADE: Every time I see her,
it's like the first time...
but there was a line that he drew in terms
of exactly what he'd be willing to say.
Especially from this angle.
WERNER Fortunately.
Just Ryan's face right here, it's just...
Wow, it's just...
REESE: Yeah, I mean there are multiple
times in the movie where I feel like that.
(MUSIC FADES IN)
(MEN CHEERING)
When you first learn
you have terminal cancer,
and you're looking at Vanessa,
ANNOUNCER: You can't buy love,
but you can rent it
for three minutes.
you could freeze-frame that face
and show it to anybody
in the world and say,
(EXHALES)
"What's going on here?"
And they could tell you that
this guy is in a horrible situation.
Ah, you weak motherfucker!
And the same with this,
the longing... It just...
Come on!
Come on, get it together.
You have a really wonderful ability
This isn't about me,
this is about Vanessa.
to reveal an emotion on your face
without doing much.
WERNICK: Talk about Ryan
acting behind that...
Here we go.
REYNOLDS: Thank you.
WERNICK: Because, really,
you're in a mask here as well.
Maximum effort.
-I mean, all that makeup.
REESE". Yeah.
WERNICK: It's thick, there's glue.
You can't really move your face
as naturally as you want.
Vanessa.
Talk about what that's like.
REYNOLDS". In that instance...
In these instances, it's very helpful...
Someone out back
asking for you.
I mean, Bill Corso is so gifted at...
Something about, uh,
an old boyfriend.
You know, applying prosthetic makeup
isn't just, you know, throwing a mask
on somebody and calling it a day.
It's really like using the face
that's already there
and creating something else.
And Bill gave me that ability to really,
kind of, emote through that makeup,
and I say that he, sort of, in a weird way,
did half my job for me.
And that's true.
I mean, I would leave that makeup trailer
with really half the job done already.
I knew it was you.
And I'm so grateful
that he was on the movie.
He was my first call.
The weird,
curvy edges.
When I knew we were gonna do this movie,
when we got the green light
from the studio,
I called Bill Corso
to check if he was available.
Like a jigsaw puzzle.
And thank God he was.
WERNICK: One of the few times it was
actually not raining in Vancouver,
that we had to create rain.
REYNOLDS: (LAUGHS)
I know.
You have Wade Wilson
to thank for this.
I know.
REESE: I always wonder
if the audience is at all
genuinely surprised that it's Ajax,
and not you here.
(VANESSA GROANS)
REYNOLDS". I don't think so.
REESE". I don't think so, either.
-I think they're ahead of us.
-REYNOLDS: I know. Yeah.
Hey. Hey! Where'd she go?
Uh, I saw her head to the back.
Go get her, tiger.
Uh, I saw her
head to the back.
Go get her, tiger.
REESE: That was a sly wink
to the Spider-Man line.
REYNOLDS". Mmm-hmm.
REESE". And it comes back once more.
REYNOLDS: Yup.
REESE: And Bernadette Peters became
the link to indicate to Wade
that Vanessa was grabbed from this alley
in a violent fashion.
(SOFTLY) Fuck. Fuck!
Motherfucker!
-Wait, wait. Let's... Just...
-Cock juggling...
Wait, wait.
Let's... Just...
Cock juggling...
-We can talk about what we're gonna...
-Jiminy! Fuck face!
We can talk about
what we're gonna...
Jiminy! Fuck face!
REYNOLDS: Oh, I hit that thing hard.
Okay, or you
can hit that.
I remember that really, really fucking hurt
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Fuck! Fuck!
No, no.
All right. Hey!
my wrist. (LAUGHS)
Fuck! Fuck!
WERNICK: Oh, man.
Such an intense scene, such a...
Fuck!
Hey, um...
Whoa! Whoa!
Relax. Relax. Okay.
REYNOLDS". I gave Tim Miller
two takes of this.
Okay. I think
that's a good start.
I said, "You get two takes,
and then, that's it."
Oh, I'm gonna rip
his motherfucking...
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Wait.
Find it! Find it.
What?
-I'm gonna get angry.
-Okay. All right.
I'm gonna get angry.
Okay. All right.
All right. Okay. All right.
Here. This is Vanessa.
-What?
-No, wait. It's Francis.
What?
No, wait. It's Francis.
He wants you to come to him.
He wants you
to come to him.
REESE: This is a great little foreshadowing
of the marketing campaign
What is that?
That's the shit emoji.
-where they use those emojis...
-(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
You know, it's the turd with
the smiling face and the eyes?
...on the billboards.
I thought it was chocolate
yogurt for so long.
-I didn't realize that.
-REYNOLDS: The Deadpool, yeah.
Those all started as a text message,
you know.
I need guns.
REESE: Oh, is that right?
REYNOLDS: Deadpool emoji, yeah.
Okay, which ones?
I need all the guns!
All right. Okay.
(HEAVY METAL PLAYING)
WERNICK: Our third movie
we've had produced, Rhett and I,
and our third "Arm up, grab the gun" scene
around the house.
REESE: Yeah.
We like the arming-up scene.
REYNOLDS: Yup.
(REYNOLDS LAUGHS)
That's about 3,000 rounds.
REYNOLDS: Hugh Jackman.
We all know
what I can do with 12.
I love that Hugh Jackman does appear
in our movie in that regard
Hey, hey, careful with that,
Ronnie Milsap!
just because he is...
I often think of Hugh Jackman as the guy
We're downrange.
that kind of ushered in the cool
comic book character again
I was gonna
spend the night
assembling the Borje,
but this is holding my interest.
because when he created Wolverine,
and created that character, and...
I told you, we're going with
the Urvaj, not the Borje.
Just so...
I think it just so changed the game.
Get it through your head
or get out of fuck town.
It was a strange thing that it ushered in
Shit. That's all the pieces
in the house.
a whole new wave of comic book movies
that were cool again and...
Nah, nah... Come on.
Let's go. Cough it up.
Up, up, up.
REESE: Yeah, he's like our
spiritual godfather.
Oh. Down, down, down.
REYNOLDS". Yeah, he really is
and such a sport, you know.
Fuck you.
Was such a huge supporter of this movie
.45 cal. I like it.
and it getting made with the studio
Wade...
because he's obviously one of the biggest
stars the studio works with.
I'd go with you,
but I don't want to.
I definitely owe him a debt of gratitude.
Uh...
Listen, Al...
if I never see you again, I want you
to know that I love you very much.
if I never see
you again,
I want you to know that
I love you very much.
REESE: This was Ryan's idea,
this cocaine bit.
And also, there's about 116 kilos of cocaine
buried somewhere in the apartment...
And also, uh, there's
about 116 kilos of cocaine
buried somewhere
in the apartment...
right next to the cure for blindness.
Good luck.
right next to the cure
for blindness. Good luck.
REESE: It's this seesawing
between sentiment and emotion,
and then undercutting that
with just cynicism and cruelty.
You wanna get fucked up?
(REYNOLDS AND REESE LAUGHING)
(SEAGULLS SCREECHING)
REYNOLDS". But there's a little truth there.
I think Deadpool does really love her
and wonders if he'll ever see her again.
(MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER P.A.)
But he always has to
kind of undercut it with...
(MUMBLING)
WERNER. "Wanna get fucked up?"
The TV version that T.J...
Put her down
over here.
REYNOLDS: Oh, yeah, what was it?
WERNICK: "Wanna get felt up?"
(WHIMPERS)
REYNOLDS: Oh, yeah, which is worse.
WERNICK: Which is actually worse.
(MUMBLING CONTINUES)
REYNOLDS". So much worse
but totally fine for television.
Go on then.
Thanks, dick less. And I mean you.
Thanks, dickless.
And I mean you.
Wow. You're a talker too. You and Wade.
Wow. You're a talker too.
You and Wade.
I've been trying to tell you assholes,
you've got the wrong girl.
I've been trying
to tell you assholes,
you've got the wrong girl.
My old boyfriend, he's dead.
My old boyfriend,
he's dead.
See, I thought that too.
But he keeps on coming back.
Like a cockroach...
WERNICK: "Or like a bad Jesus."
but uglier.
REYNOLDS: There was a line
that Rhett and Paul had for...
As an alternate there,
"It keeps coming back like a bad Jesus,"
Now, I may not feel,
but he does.
and I'll always be sad that
that's not actually in the movie.
Let's see how he fights
with your head on the block.
For whatever reason, it got C-Blocked.
WERNICK: This mansion is in...
Where is this mansion?
REYNOLDS: It's in Vancouver.
WERNICK: Vancouver.
REYNOLDS". Shaughnessy area,
Vancouver, yeah.
From Alien 3!
Ripley, from Alien 3!
Fuck, you're old.
(REYNOLDS AND REESE LAUGHING)
(WERNICK CHUCKLES)
(CACKLES)
Fake laugh.
Hiding real pain.
Fake laugh. Hiding real pain.
Go get Silver Balls.
You guys going for a bite?
Early bird special?
Like there's something wrong with
eating before sundown or saving money.
Oh, like there's
something wrong
with eating before sundown
or saving money.
No, you know that bad guy
that you let go?
REYNOLDS: That's real for me, by the way.
WERNICK: Me, too.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
He's got my girl.
You're gonna help me get her back.
You're gonna
help me get her back.
COLOSSUS: Wade? Is that you?
COLOSSUS: Wade, is that you?
Yeah, it's me, Deadpool,
and I got an offer that you can't refuse.
and I got an offer
that you can't refuse.
I'm gonna wait out here, okay?
I'm gonna wait
out here, okay?
It's a big house.
It's funny that I only ever see two of you.
It's almost like the studio
couldn't afford another X-Man.
It's funny that I only
ever see two of you.
It's almost like the studio
couldn't afford another X-Man.
WERNER Ladies and gentlemen,
Ryan Reynolds.
-The genius of Ryan Reynolds right there.
-(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
-That was...
-WERNICK: Biggest laugh of the movie.
WADE: And that is why,
in my opinion...
REYNOLDS". That one I love,
it was just funny 'cause it's true.
the movie Cocoon
is pure pornography.
REESE: It is just about
the biggest laugh of the movie.
Who brought
this twinkly man?
Twinkly, but deadly.
WERNICK: I sat behind Jim Gianopulos,
who's the head of Fox,
My chrome-penised
friend back there
has agreed
to do me this solid.
when that joke played,
In exchange,
I said that I would
-and he was howling, laughing so hard.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
consider joining his boy band.
It's not boy band.
He's also laughing because it's true.
Sure it's not.
-WERNICK True, yeah.
-(REYNOLDS CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS LOUDLY) So,
any luck winning Gita back?
REESE: Colossus is written
on that Starbucks cup.
I tried to hold on tight,
Mr. Pool...
Unfortunately, you can't quite get enough
of a glimpse of it.
but Bandhu is more craftier
and handsomer than me.
But I just love the idea of him
going into the Starbucks...
Well, I think you're
pretty darn cute.
WERNICK: "What's your name?" "Colossus. "
(MAN SCREAMS)
WERNICK: That's your scream, Ryan, yes?
(PUNJABI MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
REYNOLDS: Yes, that is my scream.
Dopinder.
Hmm?
WERNICK". You play Bandhu.
REYNOLDS: I guess
I do technically play Bandhu.
What was that?
WERNICK". Are you listed
in the credits as Bandhu?
Uh...
That was Bandhu
in the trunk.
REESE". I didn't even think about that.
REYNOLDS: I don't know, I have no idea.
WERNICK: You should be.
REESE: Yeah.
REYNOLDS". I do a couple of screams
and yells for other people, too.
Ban who?
WERNICK Really?
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
My romantic rival Bandhu.
He's tied up in the trunk.
I'm doing as you said, DP.
I plan to gut him like a tandoori fish,
then dump his carcass on Gita's doorstep.
I plan to gut him
like a tandoori fish,
then dump his carcass
on Gita's doorstep.
I did not tell him to do that.
I did not tell him
to do that.
Absolutely not.
It got lost in translation.
Dopinder, this is no way
to win Gita's heart back!
(WHISPERS) I'm so proud of you.
(WHISPERS)
I'm so proud of you.
(WERNICK AND REESE CHUCKLING)
Drop Bandhu off,
safe and gentle-like.
Kill him.
(WHISPERS) Kill him.
REESE: This is a very big crowd pleaser, too,
this little bit right here.
And then,
win Gita back...
the old fashioned way:
with your boyish charm.
REYNOLDS: Love it.
(WHISPERS) Kidnap her.
Also funny 'cause it's true.
He's super dead.
Whoa!
I presume a crisp high five?
I presume a crisp
high five?
For you? 10.
Okay, guys, let's get out there
and make a difference.
(WHISPERS) You know what to do.
(WHISPERS)
You know what to do.
(REYNOLDS LAUGHS)
Knock 'em dead,
Pool Boy!
Knock 'em dead, Pool Boy!
REESE: We intended to have DMX,
X Gonna Give it To Ya, in there
Time to make
the chimi-fuckin'-changas.
from the very earliest draft of the script.
WADE: Not often
a dude ruins your face...
We just love that song and, thankfully,
it made it all the way through.
skull-stomps your sanity,
grabs your future baby mama...
and personally sees to four
WERNICK: And it's become the anthem
of the movie, in a way.
of your five
shittiest moments.
REYNOLDS: It really has.
REESE: Yeah, they used it in marketing.
REYNOLDS: Every commercial and it's...
Let's just say it's beginning
to look a lot like Christmas.
And Chimichanga, we have...
That's our Chimichanga reference there.
We had to have that in the film.
REESE: Yeah.
And, uh...
This third act action...
Tim Miller did such a wonderful job
of balancing budget vs action,
NEGASONIC TEENAGE WARHEAD:
Hey.
Where's your duffle bag?
(PHONE RINGING)
and giving us scope and scale
(HINDI SONG PLAYING ON RADIO)
-with not a lot of money in this sequence.
-REYNOLDS: Mmm.
REESE: I mean, particularly this massive
fight between Colossus and Angel Dust.
(TRUCK HONKING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
{THUDS)
-(BANDHU SCREAMS)
(THUDS)
(BANDHU SCREAMS)
DOPINDER: Bandhu?
DOPINDER: Leave a message
and have a happy day.
God damn it!
I'm gonna do this the old fashioned way...
I'm gonna do this
the old fashioned way...
with two swords and maximum effort.
with two swords
and maximum effort.
WERNICK: "Maximum effort"
was a catchphrase.
Cue the music.
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
Was that a comic catchphrase or
did you come up with that, Ryan?
REYNOLDS". Oh, I thought
you guys came up with that.
-I don't know. I love it.
-WERNICK: I can't... Yeah, yeah...
REYNOLDS". But I always thought
it was you.
WERNER I can't remember exactly
but, uh...
(MUSIC STOPS)
He uses it now three times
in the movie, I think?
REYNOLDS: Yeah, love it.
FRANCIS: Wade Wilson!
What's my name?
Oh, I'mma fuckin' spell it out for ya.
Oh, I'mma fuckin'
spell it out for ya.
WERNICK: At one point, we had, uh...
Go get some.
Superhero landing.
She's gonna do
a superhero landing.
-Stripes, Francis.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Wait for it.
WERNICK: I don't know
if you guys remember...
REYNOLDS: On the television in the bar.
WERNICK: Yup.
WADE: Whoo!
Superhero landing!
REYNOLDS". I wish it was still there but...
You know, that's really
hard on your knees.
WADE: Totally impractical. They all do it.
Totally impractical.
They all do it.
You're a lovely lady,
but I'm saving myself for Francis.
You're a lovely lady, but
I'm saving myself for Francis.
That's why I brought him.
That's why
I brought him.
I prefer not to hit a woman,
so please...
(GROANS)
I mean, that's why I brought her?
I mean,
that's why I brought her?
Oh, no, finish your tweet.
It's not... That's...
Just give us a second. Yeah.
Just give us a second.
Yeah.
There you go. Hashtag it.
There you go.
Hashtag it.
WERNER. Brianna's first
feature film role, correct?
Go get her, tiger.
REYNOLDS: I think so, yeah.
REESE: That's true.
(GROANS)
REYNOLDS: Yeah, she's a...
She was a hell of a find.
Just such a great look to her as well.
Oh, I so pity the dude who
pressures her into prom sex.
Love her hair, I love everything about her.
She's such a nice girl, too.
All right, then. Fire!
(GUNS FIRING)
WERNER The X-Men unitard.
When's the last time we saw that
in a movie? Is it ever...
REYNOLDS: Never, never.
WERNICK: Never, never.
(GRUNTS)
REYNOLDS: Nobody's ever put it in as it is
in the comics until now and...
Finish fucking her
the fuck up!
I'm very proud of that and, you know,
Language, please.
we gotta thank Tim for that as well.
Suck a cock.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Tim really was a huge supporter
of, you know, canon and
always staying faithful to the comics.
And one of the things was the
X-Suit that she's wearing.
And the other thing I...
The other big get was both
Colossus and, of course, Deadpool.
You know, his suit being
so faithful to the comics as well.
WERNICK: This is Gina actually, I think,
doing the fighting.
REESE: Oh, yeah.
WERNICK: As you know, she's MMA and...
Look away, child.
A pretty badass.
Look away!
(SCREAMING)
REYNOLDS". God, that would hurt so much
to really do that.
REESE: Oh, I know. Oh...
REYNOLDS: Every time, it makes me cringe.
WADE: Wait!
Cease fire!
Wait!
REYNOLDS". You can't see
there's a tiny shit streak
WADE: Fellas! Hey! Hey!
on that underwear that they...
That they never really
captured on film but...
You only work for that
shit-spackled muppet fart.
WERNICK: That was a real shit streak,
was it not?
So, I'mma give you a chance
REYNOLDS: It is there.
(LAUGHS)
for y'all to lay down
your firearms...
in exchange for preferential,
bordering on gentle...
Tighty-whities.
Possibly even lover-like treatment.
possibly even
lover-like treatment.
(GUNS FIRING)
Fine.
Commando!
(GRUNTING)
(EXHALING)
REYNOLDS". This is one of
my favorite pieces of action.
(GRUNTING)
So nasty but so fun.
(COLOSSUS GRUNTS)
WERNER. Your stunt double, Alex,
(ANGEL DUST GROANS)
tore his ACL in this scene.
REYNOLDS: Oh, it had just exploded
in this scene and I felt so horrible.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Because he blew his knee out
so I wouldn't blow mine out.
That's how I looked at it and...
But thankfully, it has a happy ending.
His knee is now
stronger and better than ever.
He got a great doctor and...
(GROWLS)
WERNICK: And was back shooting...
(MEN GROANING)
REYNOLDS". He was back shooting
our reshoots, you know.
He was already back doing stunts for that.
That's actually right here.
That's where he blew his knee out.
It looks like nothing,
but yeah.
WERNICK: Such a great guy.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Big, huge Deadpool fan from the Ukraine.
(GRUNTING)
And he's been a Deadpool fan
for 15 years or so.
-WERNICK: That is not Gina, actually.
-(REYNOLDS CHUCKLES)
REYNOLDS: One would hope not.
WERNICK: Nor is that.
WADE: Teabag!
Teabag!
Bob?
REESE: This always felt
very Deadpool to us that
Wade?
Oh, my God,
I haven't seen you since...
we could stop right in the middle
of a massive action scene
Jacksonville. Fridays.
Since TGI Fridays.
and have a very personal
connection, moment here.
Well, what the hell!
As ridiculous as it is.
God, come here, you.
(GRUNTS)
How are the kids? Good?
How are the kids?
Good?
And Gail?
She's still fixing that tuna casserole?
And Gail, she still fixing
that tuna casserole?
So good! But bad for the waistline,
if you know what I'm talking about.
So good.
But bad for the waistline,
if you know what
I'm talking about.
Oh! (CLEARS THROAT)
Your... On the left.
You are beautiful woman.
That is so sweet.
Uh...
Thanks.
(GRUNTS)
REESE: You know, when
you're building a cast,
you do try to anticipate the
interaction between characters.
(GROANS)
And one of the reasons we chose Colossus
is because he is a goody two-shoes.
-He is a bit of a prude.
-REYNOLDS. Mmm.
REESE: Ah, there's the name...
The name in bodies, which was...
WADE: Yoo-hoo!
FRANCIS: Does he
write you notes too?
He's such a romantic.
REYNOLDS". One guy with his pants down.
-That's overlooked a lot.
-(REESE CHUCKLES)
WADE: Don't worry, baby.
I'm comin'.
But, you know, because Colossus
is such a straight arrow,
Fire!
(GUNS FIRING)
it makes him all the more fun
opposite Deadpool,
who is a lunatic.
NEGASONIC TEENAGE WARHEAD: Hey!
NEGASONIC TEENAGE WARHEAD:
Hey!
Climb on!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
WERNICK: He becomes a little bit
of Spider-Man, here.
REYNOLDS". Yeah, it's a little bit...
A little Spider-Man. Yeah.
That jump is a little... Pushed it a little bit.
(SCREAMING)
REESE: (CHUCKLES)
I love the girlish screams.
REYNOLDS: (LAUGHS)
Oh, yeah, totally.
RE ESE: It's just not enough for him
to scream.
REYNOLDS: Deadpool is not a manly man.
He's...
(GROANING)
REESE: He's got to scream
like a 10-year-old girl.
REYNOLDS: He is part-10-year-old girl.
WERNICK: That was filmed on a, uh...
-What do they call that? A gimbal.
-REYNOLDS: A gimbal.
REYNOLDS". Yeah. It's a giant sort of
floating platform that
rotates and rocks via remote control.
Motherfucking...
REESE: Yeah, and then ultimately tilts
which gave us our, you know,
careening flight deck look.
REYNOLDS: We cut that out but this guy
grabs my leg on the ground and I...
Motherfucker should have
worn his brown pants.
I say, "Your plan to trip me to death
has failed," and then I break his neck.
Crush him.
You were right,
beautiful.
Red really is my color.
Wade?
Don't worry, baby...
I'mma get you out of that shit-box.
I'mma get you out
of that shit-box.
What better way to crawl back inside
that head of yours?
What better way to crawl back
inside that head of yours?
Oh, you never left.
But you did, asshole!
Deep breath, darling.
Ah, deep breath, darling.
Oh, wait.
Wrong choice of words.
(CHOKING)
I hope they blocked pain
to your every last nerve.
'Cause I'mma go lookin'!
I hear you grow back body parts now,
Wade.
I hear you grow back
body parts now, Wade.
When I'm finished...
parts will have to grow back you.
parts will have
to grow back you.
Good one.
Yep, that was a good one.
Let's dance.
REYNOLDS: I think that was like an
impromptu fourth wall break.
I don't know if that was ever meant
to be a fourth wall break until we...
And by dance, I mean...
let's try to kill each other.
WERNICK: And makes me laugh.
And again...
(GRUNTING)
(METAL CLANKING)
REYNOLDS: ...did it there.
WERNICK: Another one I say
around the house.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, it's a good one.
REESE: We call Ryan "The Elevator".
Because he elevates
every single thing he's in.
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
REYNOLDS". Now, you're just
being sweet to me.
REESE: No, I...
REYNOLDS: Come on, now.
REESE: No, I'm serious. You don't...
(GROANS)
REYNOLDS: We worked...
I'll say that we all...
Us three work together
very, very, very well.
And I hope we get to work together until
we're all very, very old and grayer.
-Both Rhett and I are already...
-(REESE CHUCKLES)
...getting gray whereas Paul...
WERNICK: Oh, come on.
I'm just gray as can be.
-REESE: (MOCKING) Dye job. Dye job.
-(WERNICK CHUCKLES)
REYNOLDS: Totally, 100%.
(COLOSSUS GROANING)
(GROANS)
(CHOKING)
WERNER The music
that's about to kick in here was, uh,
originally John Denver.
REYNOLDS". Sure was, wasn't it?
WERNICK: Rhett was a massive
John Denver fan.
Fine. Fists.
REYNOLDS: I do love the John Denver song.
Oh, sounds like
your last Saturday night.
WERNICK: Or is a massive John Denver fan.
REESE: Of course.
-Still am.
-WERNICK: Still is.
(GRUNTING)
REYNOLDS". It's one of the few times that
we've had to change music for the film
that I thought we actually improved on.
REESE: And Chicago took its place.
I'm also a huge Chicago fan.
So it felt like a lateral move to me.
But it's. ..
-WERNICK: Rhett's an easy listener.
-(ALL LAUGHING)
REYNOLDS: But how hard it is... It was hard.
It's hard to pick the music for Deadpool
because it has to be ironic.
But it still has to be good
and emotional and it's...
So you're not really picking songs that,
you know, are, sort of,
(GROANING)
one-hit-wonder, sucky songs.
You're picking songs that are slightly
legendary but also slightly ironic.
-So it's got a weird tone.
-WERNICK: Yeah.
REYNOLDS". It's always tough,
picking the songs.
(GRUNTING)
REESE: Yeah, but also easy to pick
the songs, in a way, too.
(VANESSA GROANS)
Because it's so freeing.
-You can think of any genre...
REYNOLDS: True.
...if it works for the moment.
REYNOLDS". But when you hear one
that works,
-you know it works right away.
REESE". That's true.
REYNOLDS: Whereas we always knew
right away if something wouldn't work.
WERNICK: Tim had this idea of putting these
-animated cartoon characters.
-REYNOLDS: Cartoon.
WERNICK: And really bizarre and fucked up
but awesome at the same time.
REYNOLDS". Yeah.
WERNICK". In this particular scene.
-(REYNOLDS HUMMING)
-WERNICK: Again, here's our love story
and then undercut with...
(REYNOLDS LAUGHING)
Asshole!
Oh, I always enjoy that moment.
This is a great example of sound mixing
you're gonna see here
where they just pump the song up
(FRANCIS GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
right when we need it.
You'll hear it, just gonna... Pop.
WERNICK: You know,
just the little visual effect
(GRUNTING)
of the blood popping out there.
-Tim is such a VFX maestro, you know.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
WERNICK: He owns a VFX company
here in Los Angeles.
And it's just really how he got his start.
(EXPLODING)
And is just brilliant at it and, you know,
you can see it in this entire third act.
REYNOLDS: Weirdly you can't do that
little thing in a PG-13 movie.
That's, I mean... That's just one of the
billion things that we were able to do
(GRUNTING)
with this movie as a rated-R film
that we couldn't have done otherwise.
REESE: Yeah, we really do owe thanks
to Jim Gianopulos and Stacey Snider
and Emma Watts for allowing us
to do this R.
There's obviously a glass ceiling
on box-office grosses.
(SCREAMS)
You make a lot less with an R-rated movie
than you do with a PG-13 movie.
Hang in there,
baby!
And they were willing to
sacrifice those hard dollars
Wade!
I gotcha!
for this crazy, creative experience.
And we should really thank them for that.
I got a plan.
You're not gonna like it.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, and we also, you know...
(GRUNTING)
I personally throw them
under the bus all the time
as a joke in the media when
we're talking about DeadpooL but...
The real story is that they were 100%
supportive of this film being an R-rated film
Shit! Shit! Shit!
and 100% supportive of sacrificing,
(VANESSA SCREAMING)
like you said,
that huge amount of money
Don't worry.
I'm totally on top of this.
to deliver an authentic Deadpool
that the fans deserve so...
(PANTING)
WERNICK: You know that this movie
is many things and, uh...
It's an apple amongst oranges.
Ah! Damn it!
You know, there's an over saturation of
superhero movies out there.
Maximum effort!
And this is unlike all of them.
Because it is R and
it does break all the rules.
(VANESSA SCREAMS)
REYNOLDS". We were lucky, though,
you know, we...
This movie could've been made
six years ago and I don't...
I don't know that it would be as
effective just given the fact that
we were in a climate of just extraordinary
saturation of superhero movies.
And we're at that intersection where
(RUMBLING)
it's kind of, you know, ready...
We're ready for something
a little bit different.
Big Styrofoam...
...stone.
(GRUNTS)
Thanks.
REYNOLDS: That torture device has
a five-star safety rating, as you can see,
her surviving that fall.
Just take it slow.
REESE: Yeah, that would never
protect someone in real life.
-(REYNOLDS LAUGHS)
-REESE: This is the movies.
REYNOLDS: Yes, it is.
WADE: Yoo-hoo!
WADE: Oh, my God! That was so...
Oh, my God! That was so...
(GRUNTING)
REYNOLDS: I did not perform this stunt.
I would like everyone to know.
WERNICK Oh!
REYNOLDS; But Adrian did.
My stunt... One of my stunt doubles.
Ably-.
I did this, though. I do enjoy punching.
WERNICK: Snap.
And snap.
REYNOLDS: Oh, yeah.
(EXHALING HEAVILY)
There are no words!
(FRANCIS LAUGHS)
Me and you are headed
to fix this butter face.
to fix this butterface.
What?
(CHUCKLES)
REESE". Not as uncomfortable as it looks.
You stupid fucking idiot.
-This is an entirely foam set.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Did you really think
there was a cure... for that?
REESE: You can practically jump
up and down on it like a bed.
REYNOLDS: Yeah, it was sort of fun.
What?
In a weird way... It's like one of those...
You heard me.
Gyms that's like for kids where
you get to just run around
No.
No!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
and jump on anything.
(LAUGHING
AND COUGHING)
So, you mean to say...
after all this, you can't fix me?
after all this,
you can't fix me?
REYNOLDS: I love the... Colossus has
a speech coming up about
It sounds even stupider
when you say it.
four or five moments that define a hero.
Like the kind of stupid
who admits
And this is something that
Rhett and Paul wrote that I...
he can't do the one thing
I'm keeping him alive for?
It's one of the great things about this,
I think, about this sequence,
which is that it really resonates.
It's actually... Could work very well
in any kind of superhero movie
Any last words?
and stand on its own as a dramatic
and beautiful, moving speech.
What's my name?
Who fucking cares?
Which of course we undercut
with extraordinary violence.
COLOSSUS: Wade!
Four or five moments.
REESE: Yeah, we worked
on the timing quite a bit.
I'm sorry?
We didn't want the audience to
get ahead of the gunshot
Four or five moments,
that's all it takes.
and expect it coming.
To?
But we kind of wanted them
to get ahead of it just a touch.
Be a hero.
So they were wincing, going,
(GROANS)
"You don't think he's about to possibly..."
Everyone thinks
it's a full-time job.
WERNICK: And seeing it
with an audience, they do...
Wake up a hero,
brush your teeth a hero,
-You can see them anticipating the shot...
-(REYNOLDS LAUGHS)
go to work a hero.
...and still waiting for it
and wanting it.
Not true.
Over a lifetime, there are
only four or five moments
REYNOLDS". They start
tittering, you know about...
WERNICK Yeah.
that really matter.
Moments when you're offered a choice.
Moments when you're
offered a choice.
To make a sacrifice, conquer a flaw,
save a friend...
To make a sacrifice,
conquer a flaw,
save a friend...
spare an enemy.
REYNOLDS". Right about here, they start to
sort of figure it out.
In these moments...
everything else falls away.
WERNER. What Colossus is, what, about...
What was it? $50,000 a sec?
The way the world sees us.
-(STAMMERS) What was it?
-REYNOLDS: Oh. It was something cray.
The way we...
I was like... So much of our budget
went to creating Colossus.
(RETCHING)
Why?
-But worth every penny of it.
-WERNICK: Every penny.
You were droning on.
Sure, I may be stuck looking
like pepperoni flatbread...
But at least fuck face won't heal from that.
but at least fuckface
won't heal from that.
If wearing superhero tights...
means sparing psychopaths...
then maybe I wasn't meant to wear 'em.
then maybe I wasn't
meant to wear 'em.
Not everyone monitors a hall like you.
Not everyone monitors
a hall like you.
Just promise...
Yeah, yeah, I'll be on the lookout
for the next four moments.
Yeah, yeah,
I'll be on the lookout
for the next four moments.
Oh, shit.
(WHISPERS) Oh, shit.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm just a boy...
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'm just a boy,
REESE: What movie is that from?
What movie are we referencing?
about to stand
in front of a girl...
REYNOLDS: Like Notting Hill?
WERNICK That is...
and tell her...
REESE: Maybe Notting Hill.
WERNICK: It's a...
What the fuck
am I gonna tell her?
REYNOLDS: I think it's Notting Hill.
WERNICK: Notting Hill or the other one.
Well, hmm,
you better figure it out.
REYNOLDS: It's Julia Roberts I thought of.
I'm just a girl...
I can't even tell you...
(GRUNTS)
I deserved that.
That, too.
-REESE: I think it is.
-"...standing in front of a boy."
No, no, no,
maybe not the nethers.
Start talking!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
For everything,
I'm sorry for leaving...
(STUTTERS) For everything,
I'm sorry for not cowboying up sooner.
I'm sorry for not
cowboying up sooner.
It's been rough
couple of years.
WERNICK: I just love this scene so much.
Rough?
It's just... Ryan and Morena just act
-the fuck out of this scene right here.
-REYNOLDS: She's so great. Ugh!
RE ESE: Every now and then you can
catch the dated references.
The "Cowboying up" was in reference
to the Boston Red Sox
I live in a crackhouse.
-cowboying up against the Yankees.
-REYNOLDS: I didn't know that. Really?
With a family of 12.
REESE: Yeah, many years ago and it's just...
Every night
we spoon for warmth.
You just go, "Oh, yeah, we really
did write this script a long time ago."
Everybody fights for Noelle.
She's the fattest.
WERNICK: But again, we're back to the
beating heart of the movie, you know.
There's nothing
that we don't share.
Floor space, dental floss,
even condoms.
The love story between
these two broken souls, you know.
REYNOLDS: I do like this sequence.
WERNICK: And the look.
REYNOLDS". Not sure everybody understood
that it was a call back
to their first meeting but...
So, you live in a house.
REESE: It seems like they catch on.
REYNOLDS: Talking about
the dire circumstances.
REESE: They catch on as the scene goes.
For a little bit there,
they don't quite get what's going on.
I should have come and found you sooner.
I should have come
and found you sooner.
But, baby, the guy under this mask,
he ain't the same one that you remember.
But, baby,
the guy under this mask,
he ain't the same one
that you remember.
You mean this mask?
REESE: Yeah, and we always thought that
the Hugh Jackman mask
under the other mask.
But again, once again
undercut emotion with comedy
and hopefully, you know...
REYNOLDS: That was
a fun phone call to Hugh.
(LAUGHING)
"Here's what we were thinking."
REESE". "Here's what we had in mind."
REYNOLDS: "How do you feel about
And this one.
"me stapling your face to my face?"
In case the other fell off.
WERNICK: And a little bit
of a cheat here because
that was supposed to be...
If you do the math right,
All right.
Yeah, just... Ow.
that was supposed to be cut out
from the People magazine.
Like a Band-Aid,
just give it a...
Owdie 5,000.
-Yeah, sexiest man but...
-REESE". But it's too big.
Wait, wait, wait...
-...it's too big, obviously.
-REYNOLDS: Couldn't fit my giant head
Are you sure?
is what you're really trying to say.
-My head is huge.
-(REESE LAUGHING)
I'm sure.
"Like an orange on a toothpick,"
to quote Mike Myers.
Wow.
Yeah.
REESE: Morena did a great job here
because she has to take
the character from very
skeptical and cynical back to
Hey.
full-on commitment in
about two minutes and...
After a brief
adjustment period...
-She did a nice job of it.
-REYNOLDS: Mmm.
and a bunch of drinks...
WERNICK: "It's a face I'd be happy to sit on."
Ladies and gentlemen, Rhett Reese.
it's a face...
-When I read that, when Rhett wrote that...
-REYNOLDS: Yeah. Love that line.
...I read it, I'm like,
"They're never making this movie."
I'd be happy to sit on.
(REYNOLDS AND REESE LAUGHING)
REESE: It hung in there for six years.
-It never got taken out.
-REYNOLDS: It did, it did. It never changed.
That's probably why the movie
wasn't made for six years.
I'm not the same
underneath this suit, either.
WERNICK: (LAUGHING) That line.
No.
Super-penis.
COLOSSUS: Come on, Wade. Language.
COLOSSUS:
Come on, Wade. Language.
Young one is present.
What are you still doing?
Get out of here.
Go make yourself useful!
You, go be a really big brother
to someone.
You, go be a really
big brother to someone.
Tell Beast to stop shitting on my lawn.
Tell Beast to stop
shitting on my lawn.
WERNICK: The Beast shitting on my lawn
was gonna be a coda that we...
And you,
chicken noodle...
Nothing compares to you.
REESE: Yeah, Paul wrote the
funniest coda ever where the Beast...
Sinead O'Connor, 1990.
Sorry.
That's all right.
You're cool.
Deadpool literally catches Beast
shitting on his lawn.
(GASPS)
REYNOLDS". Let people know
what a coda is first.
What in the ass?
Don't know
if everyone knows that.
That was not mean.
I'm proud of you!
REESE: Yes, that's the scene
at the very end,
after the credits.
And Paul just had this zany idea of what if
We will make an X-Man
of you yet, Wade.
For a second there,
we actually catch Beast
it felt like we were
three mini-lion robots...
-shitting on Deadpool's lawn...
-REYNOLDS: (LAUGHING)
coming together to form
one super robot.
...and running off
and Deadpool chasing him,
angrily holding his morning newspaper.
There's a stupid.
Yeah.
-And it was so funny.
-REYNOLDS: Nicholas Hoult was game.
He was game, he loved it.
WERNICK: Yeah, we just couldn't
make the schedule work.
And now, for the moment
I've all been waiting for.
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Come here.
REYNOLDS: Poor Morena had to...
(LAUGHS)
Not looking my best right there.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHING)
WERNICK: Again a plant
that then paid off here.
Wham! As promised.
REYNOLDS". Another song
that really stayed in this
-script from the beginning, I think, right?
-WERNICK: Yeah. Yeah.
(MAN VOCALIZING)
REYNOLDS: Thank you, George Michael,
for letting us use this.
WERNICK: And Ridgeley,
don't forget about Ridgeley.
WADE: See?
REYNOLDS: And Ridgeley, of course,
of course, of course,
You don't need to be
a superhero to get the girl.
you can't forget about him.
WADE: The right girl will bring out
the hero in you.
The right girl will bring out
Now, let's finish this epic wide shot.
Pull out.
Now, let's finish this
epic wide shot. Pull out.
There we go, that looks nice.
That's gonna be about the only thing
that's pulling out tonight.
That's gonna be
about the only thing
that's pulling out tonight.
Who doesn't love a happy ending, huh?
Who doesn't love
a happy ending, huh?
Till next time, this is your friendly
neighborhood pool guy singing...
'Til next time, this is
your friendly neighborhood
pool guy singin'...
(SINGING) I'm never gonna dance again
♪ I'm never gonna dance again
REYNOLDS: (SINGING) The way / dance
with you, oh!
♪ The way I danced with you ♪
Wow! That was like 24 walls right there.
-Me singing...
-REESE: Oh, my gosh.
...white the movie was singing
while George Michael was singing.
Yes, Rhett Reese and Paul Wernick indeed.
(REYNOLDS SINGING)
REESE: This is
a beautiful little animated sequence.
REYNOLDS: I know.
This was kind of a late addition, too.
-Really happy with it.
-REESE: It was.
I can't remember. Tim hired
just this brilliant guy to do it.
And I'm spacing his name.
WERNICK: The same guys who did the...
REYNOLDS: Who did the cartoons...
WERNICK: The cartoons
in the stab scene, yeah.
REESE: Right.
-The little heart with the arms and legs.
-REYNOLDS: Yeah.
Also known as Junkie XL.
Great... Great guy.
WERNER Just a brilliant group of people
who came together to make this
and a bunch of great guys
on top of it and women and...
And men, children...
REESE". Yeah, and we also really...
REYNOLDS: Do you really have
to talk about children
-while an animated boner is on the screen?
{REESE LAUGHS)
WERNICK Yeah.
REESE: Collectively stood on
all the giants' shoulders
who created Deadpool, Rob Liefeld
and all the wonderful writers who...
And artists who brought Deadpool to life
for so many years
-before he became a movie. Yeah.
-WERNICK: Fabian.
REYNOLDS". Fabian, yeah,
just all these guys, yeah.
(LAUGHING)
I love that little sequence.
WERNICK". Salt-n-Pepa.
REYNOLDS". That was another song
that reflect... We had, in the movie,
initially, in every place that
Sheep is in and it was just too
damn expensive, so we ended up
with Sheep, but in a weird way
Shoop was better.
It works so much better and...
-WERNICK: Yeah.
-...it worked with the tone of the movie
in a great way.
REYNOLDS". Here is where you'll get to see
if I was Bandhu or not...
-WERNICK: Oh, yeah.
-...in the credits. I don't think I was, though.
Nope. Hmm. Oh, well...
REESE". So Bandhu is not even listed.
REYNOLDS". I'm uncredited, yeah.
WERNICK: Get me Ryan's agent
on line two, please.
REYNOLDS: You have two lines?
WERNICK: l do.
WERNICK: The first line
doesn't work, though...
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
REESE: Here in Ryan's house,
you have two lines?
-This is getting weird.
-REYNOLDS: Super weird.
WERNICK: I've been living in the crawlspace
for the last little bit here.
REYNOLDS: Oh.
-Joan Bierman, our post-supervisor that...
-WERNICK: Great.
REYNOLDS". There are so many people that
work on these movies that
are never front and center, but just
they work so goddamn hard.
And Joan is one of them. Joan just...
Day in and day out, just gave this movie
her last drop of blood in post.
It was an accelerated post on this film
because Fox gave us very tittie time
between shooting and our release date
to get this movie completely finished and
ready for its audience and...
And a key component to that success
is Joan Bierman.
WERNICK: We started shooting in March of
-2015?
-REYNOLDS'. Not true, April.
Because we'd already... Remember we
shot the April Fools' gag with Mario Lopez
and then started shooting which was...
WERNICK: Is that right? Yeah, you're right.
REYNOLDS". I think it was like April 4
we started shooting.
REESE: Wow.
WERNICK: Yeah, and you know it came
out in, or it's coming out in February.
So that's a what? A 10-month turnaround?
REYNOLDS: Yeah.
WERNICK: And with
all the visual effects and...
-Just amazing.
-REYNOLDS: Really tough.
Tough, tough deadline to meet but...
What's that great expression that the task
expands for the time allotted,
-or something like that?
-REESE: Yeah, exactly.
REYNOLDS". It seems to be
about right for this, yeah.
WERNICK: And we're actually
nine days away
from the movie actually releasing.
REYNOLDS". Yeah, as we record this,
we're nine days out.
REESE: So we have no idea whether
this has a happy ending.
REYNOLDS: (LAUGHING) Yeah, that's true.
REESE: We know whether this session 's
gonna have a happy ending.
WERNICK: What? What?
REYNOLDS: Absolutely.
I got two hands, one for each of you.
WERNICK: "I bet it feels huge in this hand."
(REESE AND REYNOLDS LAUGH)
REESE: There's a general
misconception that,
well, I don't know how
much of a misconception it is,
that everybody in Hollywood's out just
lying on the beach and
we're all doing cocaine
and yeah, yeah, maybe those things
happen now and again.
But what's really happening is
everybody is working their butt off.
Like these are...
When you watch a movie like this and
you watch these names
just drift past, these are people
who worked 18, 19-hour days often,
back to back to back to back,
to bring this to life so
I'm just gonna stand up
for the people of Hollywood.
And remind everybody how hard they work
to make this magic happen.
REYNOLDS". Absolutely, and in a lot of
different cities, too,
not just Los Angeles
but all over the country
-and all over the world, frankly. Yeah.
REESE". Yeah, Vancouver.
And our VFX
was done all over the place.
It's just, you know, when you're a citizen
and these movies come out in theaters,
you think they just come out.
And you don't realize the
many, many years of labor.
REYNOLDS: No.
And all those people put their...
Put their blood, sweat and tears
into the ones that work.
And they put the same blood, the
same sweat, the same tears into the ones
-that don't work.
REESE". Like this one.
-I'm kidding.
-REYNOLDS: (LAUGHS) Wow!
REESE: This one is awesome, we love it.
REYNOLDS: Oh, we do love it.
I quite literally miss shooting
this film. (CHUCKLES)
And a special thanks, with tongue,
to Rob Liefeld and Fabian.
WERNICK: Did they break the...
The two codas here?
Or is it one long coda at the end?
I don't know how we ended up on that.
REYNOLDS". It's one long one. Yeah.
WERNICK: Is it?
Captioned by Deluxe
REYNOLDS". Yeah, this full coda
was never shown to...
-At the fan screenings or test audiences.
-WERNICK: Test audiences, yeah.
REESE: Whose idea was
the Ferris Bueller thing?
REYNOLDS: I don't remember.
You're still here?
I thought it was one of you guys.
WERNER. Yeah, I think that was me.
It's over. Go home.
REESE: Yeah, I think
that was you, wasn't it?
I couldn't remember.
Expecting a teaser for Deadpool 2.
Well, we don't have that kind of money.
Oh, you're expecting
a teaser for Deadpool 2.
Well, we don't have
that kind of money.
What are you expecting?
Sam Jackson to show up?
With an eye patch and a...
With an eye patch and a saucy
little leather number?
WERNER They made us change
the wallpaper, Paramount Pictures.
Go. Go.
REYNOLDS". 'Cause it was too damn close...
Maybe it is broken up...
'Cause it was too damn close to the
original Ferris Bueller wallpaper.
Oh.
WERNICK: So I think Tim put in
some penises onto the wallpaper.
But I can tell you one thing,
and it's a bit of a secret.
For the sequel,
we're gonna have Cable.
REYNOLDS: Yes.
WERNICK: If you look closely...
REYNOLDS". There are penises
in the wallpaper.
Amazing character.
Bionic arm, time travel.
WERNICK: I'm not kidding.
REYNOLDS: No, there are, yeah.
We have no idea
who we're gonna cast yet,
REESE: I don't see any.
but it could be anybody.
Just need a big guy
with a flat top.
-REYNOLDS: You wouldn't!
-(ALL CHUCKLING)
Could be Mel Gibson,
Dolph Lundgren...
Keira Knightley.
She's got range. Who knows.
Anyway, big secret. Shh.
Anyway, big secret. Shh...
And don't leave your garbage all lying
around. It's a total...
Oh, and don't leave your
garbage all lying around.
It's a total dick move.
WERNER That was a nod
to Tim Miller who hates
people who leave their garbage
at movie theaters.
Go.
I am among them.
(WADE VOCALIZES)
(VOCALIZES)
Doctors Advice
www.doc-advice.com